music
音楽
applause
拍手
Today's meeting was supposed to be hosted by the vice president of our Humanities Society
今日の会議は私たちの人文科学協会の副会長が主催するはずだった
But it just so happens that he is not here today because of a pharmacist, and even the vice presidents are very busy, so there is no way
でも今日はたまたま薬剤師の都合で来ていないのと、副社長たちも忙しいので仕方がありません。
So I had to be represented by Quan Cong, and I would like to say sorry to the host
そのため、Quan Cong にこのカンファレンスの代表をさせざるを得ませんでした。主催者には申し訳ありませんと言いたいと思います。
Today's keynote speaker is Director Hu Xiaozhen. He is the director of the Institute of Culture and Philosophy and is currently a researcher of the Institute.
本日の基調講演者は、文化哲学研究所の所長であり、現在は同研究所の研究員でもある胡暁鎮所長です。
Everyone will know after listening to his speech that he is very knowledgeable, so I am also very happy to have this opportunity today
彼のスピーチを聞いたら、彼が非常に知識が豊富であることは誰もが知っているので、今日このような機会を得ることができて私もとてもうれしく思います
Enjoy this voice of his literary novel
彼の文学小説の声をお楽しみください
Director Hu is a PM from the Wanwen Department of National Taiwan University and a master of literature from De Yaguo, California.
胡監督は国立台湾大学万文学部のPMであり、カリフォルニア州デ・ヤグオで文学の修士号を取得しています。
Dean of East Asian Civilizations at Harvard University
ハーバード大学東アジア文明学部長
A Ph.D. with Mingxi Wu
ミンシー・ウーで博士号を取得
Works and other students
著作等生
numerous awards
数々の賞を受賞
In 1999, he won the Young Works Award of our middle school
1999年、彼は本校中学校の若手作品賞を受賞しました。
Awarded by the National Science Council in 2003
2003年に米国科学会議から賞を受賞
Wu Great Excellence Award
呉大優秀賞
This is very difficult in academia
これは学問の世界では非常に難しいことです
An award for young scholars
若手研究者への賞
that 2012
その2012年
Also got the special book on humanities and society from our middle school
中学校からも人文社会専門書をいただきました
First Book Award
第一回図書賞
so visible
とても目に見える
He has a lot of heart on his body
彼の体にはたくさんの心が詰まっている
His main research
彼の主な研究
Mainly in the literature and art of Ming and Qing Dynasties
主に明・清時代の文学と芸術
and this
この
Especially in the subject of the main prize for women's literature he's waiting for
特に彼が待ち望んでいる女性文学の主要賞のタイトルでは
he this
彼はこれ
Published several books
数冊の本を出版
I'm not here
私はここにはいません
a fastest
最速の
That
それか
The topic of his speech today will be the master. Wait until everyone sees him.
今日の彼のスピーチの主題はマスターです。みんなが彼に会うまで待ってください。
Chai girl, Chai girl, Chai girl and the like
チャイガール、チャイガール、チャイガールなど
His raised head is very appropriate to himself
彼の上げた頭は彼自身にとても似合っています
It mainly focuses on the emotion and imagination of women's novels in the Qing Dynasty
主に清朝の女性小説の感情と想像力に焦点を当てています。
Now, all distinguished guests, please welcome our Director Hu Xiaosheng
それでは、ご来賓の皆様、胡暁生所長をお迎えください。
Thanks
ありがとう
Peng Ding long
彭定書長
Dear friends inside and outside the hospital
病院内外の親愛なる友人の皆様
I am Hu Xiaozhen from Literary Institute
私は文学研究院の胡暁鎮です。
It is a great honor to be invited to the knowledge feast of our Academia Sinica today
本日は中央研究院の知識の饗宴にご招待いただき大変光栄です
Let me share with you some of my research experience
私の研究経験の一部を共有させてください
In fact, there are studies on women's literature in the Ming and Qing Dynasties
実際、明・清時代の女性文学に関する研究もある。
not my new research
私の新しい研究ではありません
Or Wu Ning said she was my earlier actor
あるいは、ウーニンは彼女が私の以前の俳優だと言った
But I think sometimes it's a new era
でも時々、それは新しい時代だと思う
Can exchange for a new meaning
新しい意味と交換できる
I do research on this
私はこれについて研究しています
Actually from the 90s
実は90年代から
but since the 90s
しかし90年代以降
and my related book published in 2003
および 2003 年に出版された私の関連書籍
in the process
過程の中で
I think the acceptance of women's literature and women's issues
女性文学と女性問題の受容だと思います。
In fact, it is far from being as high as everyone's concern about related issues now.
実際、現在、関連問題に対するみんなの関心はそれほど高くありません。
So I want to bring this topic back here
そこでこの話題をここに戻したいと思います
Come and enjoy with everyone
みんなで遊びに来てね
let's feel together
一緒に感じましょう
Let's criticize together
一緒に批判しましょう
Maybe it still has new meaning
もしかしたらまだ新しい意味があるかもしれない
So today's topic
ということで今日の話題は
I don't know what you think when you see the title
タイトルを見たらどう思うか分かりませんが、
So from talented women to talented women who are not beautiful
つまり、才能のある女性から、美しくない才能のある女性へ
Talented girls are already so tired
才能のある女の子はもう疲れている
why don't you say
なぜ言わないのですか
go to bed
寝る
why doesn't he want to sleep
なぜ彼は寝たくないのですか
or why can't sleep
それともなぜ眠れないのか
in fact
実際には
this here
これはここです
Words like rich girl
金持ちの娘のような言葉
not what we usually say
私たちが普段言っていることではありません
oh so tired
ああ、とても疲れた
Very sleepy
とても眠い
so tired
すごく疲れた
The class that really wants to sleep
本当は寝たいクラス
what about this class
このクラスはどうですか
I actually borrowed one
実際に借りてみた
American sinologist
アメリカの中国学者
Called Ronald Egan
ロナルド・イーガンと呼ばれる
Professor Ellen Knoll
エレン・ノール教授
to the Song Dynasty
宋の時代へ
famous female writer
有名な女性作家
Li Qingzhao's research
李清照氏の研究
What about his original text?
彼の原文はどうでしょうか？
is called
と呼ばれます
The Burden
負担
one attached to him
一つは彼に付いている
something he didn't want
彼が望まなかった何か
So
それで
The Sinologist pointed out
中国学者は指摘した
that's not what i said
それは私が言ったことではありません
It's what Professor Elonor thinks
エロノア教授はこう考えている
He said that in traditional society
彼は伝統的な社会ではこう言った
Literary sanctions for women are a major
女性に対する文学的制裁は重大である
why
なぜ
Because male literati intellectuals
男性文人知識人だから
scholars, officials, etc.
学者、役人など。
the entire mainstream society
主流社会全体
talented for women
女性にとって才能のある
And put it on the creation of literature and art
そしてそれを文学と芸術の創造に置きます
this thing is not satisfactory
これは満足のいくものではありません
is biased
偏見がある
They believe that women should not engage in literary and artistic creation
彼らは女性が文学や芸術の創作に携わるべきではないと信じている
Then the male literati are against such behavior
すると男性文人たちはそのような行為に反対する
is suppressed
抑制されている
And what's worse than creating it is
そして、それを作成することよりも悪いことは、
Spread the good work
良い取り組みを広めてください
because for the ancients
なぜなら古代人にとっては
A woman's handwriting is like a part of her
女性の手書き文字は自分の一部のようなもの
So for a person who should not put himself
だから、自分を置いてはいけない人にとっては、
a woman exposed to public society
社会にさらされた女性
If the work is exposed to the eyes of the public
作品が公衆の目にさらされた場合
that is also an exposure
それも暴露です
So this public literary work
つまり、この公共文学作品は、
It's actually an inappropriate behavior
実は不適切な行為なのです
Then under the constraints of this society
そしてこの社会の制約の中で
the woman writer herself
女性作家自身
no matter how well she writes
彼女がどんなに上手に書いたとしても
no matter how lonely she was
たとえ彼女がどんなに孤独だったとしても
She has no way to feel at ease
彼女には安心する方法がない
spread your work
あなたの作品を広めてください
So most authors will choose
したがって、ほとんどの著者は選択するでしょう
take her work
彼女の仕事を引き受ける
burn it
それを燃やす
Or destroy her all before she dies
それとも死ぬ前に彼女を全て破壊するか
This will ensure
これにより、
she is an innocent
彼女は無実です
pure, respectable
純粋な、立派な
this elite woman
このエリート女性
then such thoughts
それからそのような考え
It is completely different from our modern people
現代人とは全く違います
so what
だから何
The Song Dynasty was not without women's writing
宋の時代には女性の著作がなかったわけではない
But none of their works have been well circulated.
しかし、彼らの作品はどれも十分に流通していません。
Then Professor Alan Rowe pointed out
そこでアラン・ロウ教授はこう指摘した。
Li Qingzhao is here
李青照はここにいます
Among the many women who can write
文章を書くことができる多くの女性の中で、
the most special one
最も特別なもの
Because he not only insisted on creating
なぜなら、彼はただ創造することを主張しただけではないからです。
And he's not shy
そして彼は恥ずかしがり屋ではありません
even hard
たとえ大変でも
spread your work
あなたの作品を広めてください
And he also tried hard to shape himself into a
そして彼はまた、自分自身を形作るために一生懸命働きました
a man of letters
文豪
Can sit on an equal footing
対等な立場で座ることができる
so as of today
だから今日から
The Li Qing Dynasty is still at the top of the history of Chinese literature
李清王朝は依然として中国文学史上の頂点に君臨する
almost the only one
ほぼ唯一の
a woman writer with classic status
古典的な地位を持つ女性作家
how to prove it
それをどうやって証明するか
I don't know everyone
みんなは知りません
We often read news reports
私たちはニュースレポートをよく読みます
about a few months ago
数ヶ月ほど前
Dean Liao
ディーン・リャオ
when in the legislature
議会にいるとき
He was asked by a legislator on the spot and said
その場で議員に質問されてこう言った。
May I ask Dean Liao if you can
できればディーン・リャオに聞いてもいいですか
Can you recite a few classical poems?
古典的な詩をいくつか暗唱していただけますか。
I think Secretary-General Peng must still remember
彭事務総長は今でも覚えているはずだ
So what did Dean Liao say?
結局、廖ディーンは何と言ったのでしょうか？
Dean Liao blurted out that
ディーン・リャオはこう口走った。
oh look for secrets
ああ、秘密を探してください
desolate
荒涼とした
Qiqi miserable
チーチーは惨めだ
seven seven
七七
Right? Whose work is this?
そうでしょう？これは誰の作品ですか？
This is Li Qingzhao's "Sound Man" in the
これは李清照の「サウンドマン」です。
This is of course a drama
これはもちろんドラマです
Then it can be proved that
そうすれば次のことが証明できる
even after a thousand years
千年経っても
For the leader of an academic hall
学術館のリーダーにとって
This Ming opera by Li Qingzhao
李清照作の明のオペラです。
Still one of the most classic words in his mind
今でも彼の心の中で最も古典的な言葉の一つです
It can be seen that Li Qingzhao, a female author,
女性作家の李青照さんは、
A special place in the history of Chinese literature
中国文学史上特別な場所
But it is also because Li Qingzhao
でもそれは李青照のせいでもある
His literary reputation is so great
彼の文学的名声は非常に高い
So this real Li Qingzhao
つまり、この本物の李青照
What kind of a woman is that?
それはどんな女性ですか？
His face became blurred instead.
代わりに顔がぼやけてしまいました。
will be shaded and distorted
陰影がついて歪んでしまいます
How to say it? For example
どう言えばいいでしょうか?例えば
Where's Li Qingzhao?
李青兆はどこですか？
Everyone knows that his husband is called Zhao Mingcheng
彼の夫は趙明成という名前であることは誰もが知っています
The two of them are very knowledgeable couple
お二人はとても知識豊富なご夫婦です
They are very emotional
彼らはとても感情的です
But Zhao Mingcheng unfortunately died in the middle age
しかし、趙明成は残念ながら中年で亡くなりました。
after death
死後
Li Qingzhao has nothing to rely on
李青照には頼るものがない
he actually made a decision
彼は実際に決断を下した
He remarried
彼は再婚した
Then he not only remarried
その後、彼は再婚しただけでなく、
Moreover, within a short period of time, he
さらに、彼は短期間のうちに、
found he couldn't stand this second husband
彼はこの二番目の夫に我慢できないことがわかった
So he went to sue the second husband
それで彼は二番目の夫を訴えに行きました
Said that he had all kinds of illegal situations
彼はあらゆる種類の違法な状況にあったと述べた
constant behavior etc.
一定の行動など
And in the end, if you win this lawsuit, you will be able to get a divorce.
そして最終的にこの訴訟に勝てば離婚できることになります。
So what about such a life experience?
では、そのような人生経験はどうでしょうか？
It was very illegal for the people at the time.
当時の人々にとってそれは非常に違法でした。
The first one is that remarriage itself may be stigmatized
1つ目は、再婚自体が非難される可能性があるということです。
The second one immediately filed a lawsuit after remarrying and said they wanted a divorce.
二人目は再婚後すぐに訴訟を起こし、離婚したいと言いました。
This may also be on the social news page today
これは今日のソーシャル ニュース ページにも掲載される可能性があります
Then let alone sending a loan
それではローンを送るどころか
So for a long, long time
だから長い間、長い間
Li Qingzhao's life experience
李青照さんの人生経験
Everyone doesn't know how to face him
誰もが彼とどう向き合っていいのか分からない
Then some people started this harsh criticism
それから何人かの人々がこのような厳しい批判を始めました
This is called nonsense
こういうのをナンセンスって言うんだよ
That is to say, this lady Li Qingzhao
つまり、この女性、李青照さんです。
so unruly
とても手に負えない
It can be seen that there is no need to read her works
彼女の作品を読む必要がないことがわかります
this is a way of saying
これは言い方です
Another way is to reverse
もう一つの方法は逆にすることです
Maybe it's because I love her work so much.
それは私が彼女の作品をとても愛しているからかもしれません。
So especially during the Qing Dynasty
特に清朝時代には
There are other scholars and literati
他にも学者や文人がいる
I tried my best to excuse Li Qingzhao
私は李青照を全力で弁解しようとした
To say that the previous stories are all false
これまでの話が全部ウソだと言うのは
Li Qingzhao didn't change the price at all
Li Qingzhao は価格をまったく変更しませんでした
He always loves Zhao Mingcheng alone
彼はいつも趙明成を一人で愛していた
It's for him to keep the truth and cleanliness till the end
最後まで真実と潔白を保つのは彼のためだ
Only in this way can he be a pure and innocent talented woman
そうすることでしか彼は純粋無垢な才女になれるのです
such an identity
そんなアイデンティティ
Such an image was handed down to later generations
そんなイメージが後世に受け継がれた
Then we see that no matter the former
そうすれば、前者に関係なく、
Or the latter understanding of Li Qingzhao
あるいは後者の李清照の理解
There may be a considerable distance from the real Li Qingzhao
本物の李青照とはかなりの距離があるかもしれない
Then we until the twentieth century
それから私たちは20世紀まで
Only then did I have the opportunity to take Li Qingzhao's body
そのとき初めて、私は李青照さんの遺体を引き取る機会を得ました。
Those heavy shackles that we have given
私たちが与えたその重い足かせ
The so-called Burden
いわゆる負担
slowly remove
ゆっくりと取り外します
let's meet
会いましょう
This one can see Lu Qingzhao's real face
これは陸青照の素顔を見ることができます
We now see Lu Qingzhao
ルー・チンジャオが見えてきました
It is a real attempt to
それは本当の試みです
To break through the mainstream society of the Song Dynasty
宋代の主流社会を打破する
Some Expectations and Limitations for Your Woman
あなたの女性に対する期待と限界
it can hold on to creation
それは創造を保持することができます
And try hard to spread its works
そしてその作品を広めるために努力してください
And it doesn't just write
そして、ただ書くだけではありません
Searching for secrets deserted
人けのない秘密を探して
Qiqi residual seven seven
七七殘殘七七
not just write
ただ書くだけではなく
Walking with the book wind last night
昨夜與書風走
sleepless nights
眠れない夜
Exam Questionnaire Confused
試験のアンケートが混乱している
Begonia is still
ベゴニアはまだです
Do you know
あなたは知っていますか
Because it is green, fat, red and thin
緑で太って赤くて細いから
right
右
Such a work that expresses personal and private emotions
個人的で私的な感情を表現したこのような作品
Although moving
移動しながらも
but can't
でもできない
All on behalf of Li Qingzhao
すべて李清照を代表して
Well, this Professor Elano
さて、このエラノ教授
He specifically mentioned
彼は具体的に言及した
for example
例えば
This Li Qingzhao wrote a lot
この李清照はたくさんのことを書きました
to reflect on history
歴史を振り返る
even to respond
応答することさえ
Works of the current situation in the great era
偉大な時代の現状を描いた作品
For example, he has a poem that says
たとえば、彼には次のような詩があります。
life valentines day
人生のバレンタインデー
death is ghost
死は幽霊だ
So far, I have been thinking about refusing to cross Jiangdong
今のところ、江東を越えることを拒否しようと考えています。
He said
彼は言った
to this person
この人に
Born as a dragon and phoenix among human beings
人間の中に龍と鳳として生まれる
Even if you die, you are still a hero among ghosts
死んでも幽霊の中では英雄だよ
Although some people say
という人もいますが、
towards the time of defeat
敗戦の時へ
Some people say you run away
あなたが逃げていると言う人もいます
If you escape to Jiangdong, you can temporarily save your life
江東省に逃げれば一時的に命は助かる
aftereffect
後遺症
But Xiang Yu said he would rather
しかし項羽は、むしろそうしたいと言いました。
Never want to be a waste of time
決して時間の無駄にはなりたくない
refused to cross Jiangdong
江東越えを拒否した
refused to flee to Jiangdong
江東への逃亡を拒否した
So
それで
Compared with what Li Qingzhao faced at that time
当時の李青照の直面した状況と比較して
Northern Song Army City
北宋軍城
The scene of hurriedly fleeing all the way to the south
急いで南へ逃げる場面
Of course we can imagine the poem
もちろん詩を想像することもできます
In fact, it is entrusted to Li Qingzhao
実は李清照に託されている
Li Qingzhao's view on the male-dominated society of the Northern Song Dynasty
北宋時代の男性優位社会に対する李青照の見解
and dissatisfaction with the political situation
そして政治情勢への不満
Then also through these big historical perspectives
そして、これらの大きな歴史的視点を通じて
and reflective works on politics and society
政治や社会を反映した作品
Li Qingzhao did win over
李青照は勝った
The position of literati who can sit on an equal footing with male literati
男性文人と対等な立場にある文人の立場
Okay, so far, I should actually be helping you read.
さて、ここまでは実際にあなたが読むのを手伝っているはずです。
A general summary and description of recent years
近年の概要と説明
Whether it is Chinese literature or not
中国文学であろうがなかろうが
Or the Western Sinology circles
あるいは西洋中国学サークル
Some New Viewpoints on Li Qingzhao's Problem in the Song Dynasty
宋代の李青照の問題に関するいくつかの新しい視点
then i guess this
それならこれだと思います
You might like to watch a short video of this
この短いビデオをご覧になるとよいでしょう
very troublesome for you
あなたにとってとても迷惑です
This section is from Taiwan
このセクションは台湾からのものです
Guo Gongliang Culture and Education Foundation
郭公良文化教育財団
A Jinkun play that just ended
終わったばかりのジンクン劇
The so-called Jin Kun is on this stage
いわゆるジンクンがこのステージにいます
Some roles sing golden operas
黄金のオペラを歌う役もある
Some bloody singing this kunqu opera
この昆曲オペラを血なまぐさい歌っている人もいる
Then this play is called "Qing Hui Lang Zhao"
そして、この劇は「清輝朗昭」と呼ばれます。
It describes the relationship between Li Qingzhao and his two husbands
李青照と彼の前の2人の夫との関係が描かれています。
Of course the first husband was a spy.
もちろん最初の夫はスパイだった。
With the second husband is the complete wish
2番目の夫との結婚は完全な願望です
Then obviously we can see
そうすれば明らかにわかります
What about contemporary opera?
現代劇はどうでしょうか？
Make a big fuss about Li Qingzhao's two marriages
李青照の二度の結婚について大騒ぎする
trying to drag this traditional
この伝統を引きずろうとしている
Really knot the burden of women's morality
女性の道徳の重荷を本当に結びつける
But let's look at this first
でも、まずはこれを見てみましょう
After we read it, maybe we can think
読んだ後、私たちは考えることができるかもしれません
So in the interpretation of modern people, whether we
したがって、現代人の解釈では、
We gave another woman like Li Qizhao
私たちはLi Qizhaoのような別の女性を与えました
Added a new burden
新たな負担が加わった
Let's see what this passage actually is
この一節が実際に何なのか見てみましょう
An official introduction to the play
劇の公式紹介
only 30 seconds
わずか30秒
Okay, it's over, so I don't know if any of you guys are going to see this play.
さて、もう終わってしまったので、この劇を観に行く人がいるかどうかはわかりません。
But we can see from this short introduction
しかし、この短い紹介からわかるのは、
Li Qingzhao actually has a new Birden, right?
李青照は実は新しいバーデンを持っているんですよね？
He is now burdened with a modern divorced woman
彼は今、離婚した現代の女性という重荷を負っている
A classical image of what happened
何が起こったかの古典的なイメージ
is this a new
これは新しいですか
burden?
重荷？
In my opinion it must be
私の意見ではそうであるはずです
good
良い
I want to do it again, maybe I have a lot of friends
またやりたい、友達がたくさんいるかもしれない
It's actually for Li Qingzhao
実は李青照のためだ
I was deceived by the name of that rich girl or something.
あの金持ちの娘か何かの名前に騙された。
dont know if it is like this
こんなものなのか分からない
But what?
でも何？
Li Qingzhao is just the background of our speech today
李青照氏は今日の私たちのスピーチの背景にすぎません
Actually my topic today
実は今日の私の話題は
A female writer in the Ming and Qing Dynasties, especially the Qing Dynasty
明・清時代、特に清朝の女性作家。
and a novelist
そして小説家
So why use Li Qingzhao who was sent to the generation as the background?
では、なぜ世代に送り込まれた李青照を背景に使うのでしょうか？
That's because Li Qingzhao happened to live in this era
それは、李青照がたまたまこの時代に生きていたからです。
What about the Ming and Qing Dynasties that Song Dai can tell us about?
宋代が語ってくれる明と清の時代についてはどうなのでしょうか？
make a nice print
素敵なプリントを作ってください
Well, some things don't change
まぁ変わらないものもあるけど
some things have changed
いくつかのことが変わりました
Compared with Li Qingzhao, a female writer in the Ming and Qing Dynasties
明清時代の女流作家李青照との比較
Although their creations are also restricted by many social norms
彼らの創作物も多くの社会規範によって制限されていますが、
But the Ming and Qing Dynasties
しかし、明と清の時代は
Minsei era female writer
民青時期的女作家
Their creative desires are more developed
彼らの創造的な欲求はさらに発展します
less malicious
悪意が少ない
Then their works spread far and wide
その後、彼らの作品は広範囲に広がりました
and male literati
そして男性文人
For women to engage in creative work
女性がクリエイティブな仕事に携わるために
attitude changed
態度が変わった
Many of them are very supportive
彼らの多くはとても協力的です
Then one more important thing is
それから、もう一つ重要なことは、
Minsei era female writer
民青時期的女作家
they form a group
彼らはグループを形成します
Whether it's a group in the family
家族内のグループであっても
in the same area
同じエリア内
Groups in the same area are also good
同じエリアのグループもOK
Groups in the same division are also good
同じ部門のグループもいいですね
or sometimes
または時々
just by text
文字だけで
A spiritual group is also good
スピリチュアル集団もいいですね
This feeling of being a female writer
女性作家であるというこの感覚
It was very strong during the Minqing period
明清時代には非常に強かった
and very important
そしてとても重要な
Then the women writers of this period
そしてこの時代の女性作家たちは、
some of them are wholehearted
彼らの中には心のこもった人もいます
to invest in creation
創造に投資する
and proud of it
そしてそれを誇りに思っています
Will emphasize what kind of waste you are, please forget to eat
あなたがどのような無駄であるかを強調します、食べることを忘れてください
Well, of course, this responds to the second half of the title of my speech.
もちろん、これは私のスピーチのタイトルの後半に対応しています。
Talented women are not beautiful
才能のある女性は美しいわけではない
don't sleep in order to create
創作するために寝ないでください
then we need to know
それから私たちは知る必要があります
Ability to stay awake for a job you love
好きな仕事のために起きていられる能力
it's actually a right
それは実際には権利です
It's actually not tiring
実は疲れないんです
I don't know if you feel this way
あなたがそう感じているかどうかはわかりません
I think many women working in Academia Sinica feel this way
中央研究院で働く多くの女性がそう感じていると思います
Because I like this job, I don’t sleep or get tired
この仕事が好きだから眠らないし疲れない
OK
OK
Of course, I am definitely not a woman from the Qing Dynasty
もちろん、私は決して清朝の女性ではありません。
They've gotten rid of the so-called talented women and the like
いわゆる優秀な女性などを排除してきた
actually the opposite
実際には反対です
They have to struggle with more so-called talented women
彼らはより多くのいわゆる才能のある女性たちと戦わなければならない
For example, can women pursue the livelihood of the people?
たとえば、女性は人々の生活を追求できるでしょうか？
It's not just bad people's livelihood. Women don't seem to be pursuing
人々の生活が苦しいだけではありません。女性は追求していないようです
probably good in those days
当時は良かったのかもしれない
People's livelihood should not necessarily be pursued
人々の生活は必ずしも追求されるべきではない
Because in that era, the best position for women may be to be
なぜなら、その時代において、女性にとって最良のポジションは、
deep in this
この奥深くに
this
これ
Look inside and taste inside
中を見て、中を味わう
Should not be in the public domain to shine
輝くためにはパブリックドメインにあってはなりません
so
それで
Is it a legitimate thing for these female writers to face women seeking fame?
これらの女性作家が名声を求める女性たちと対峙することは正当なことなのだろうか？
Then let alone get people's livelihood
それでは人々の生活を得るどころか
He works absolutely differently on women than on men
彼は女性に対する態度と男性に対する態度がまったく異なります
This may not have changed to this day.
これは今でも変わっていないかもしれません。
For example, the status of wife or mother
例えば妻や母親の立場
for a woman writer
女性作家にとって
Search inside, we can't think of it
中を調べてください、私たちはそれを考えることができません
Which novel was written by a woman
女性が書いた小説はどれですか
so is it true
それは本当ですか
ok then i first
わかりました、それでは私が最初に
Can you sell a pass?
パスを売ってもらえますか？
Let's start by getting everyone back from this one after dinner
夕食後にみんなをこの問題から戻すことから始めましょう
Wake up in trouble
トラブルで目覚める
So
それで
please see again
もう一度見てください
a video
ビデオ
Please go to the next PPT first
まずは次の PPT に進んでください
What I want to invite everyone to watch is the Guoguang Theater Troupe
皆さんに観ていただきたいのは國光劇団です
sorry
ごめん
What I want to invite everyone to read is a story called Meng Lijun
私が皆さんに読んでもらいたいのは、孟立軍という物語です。
In 2017 is this year
2017年は今年です
Spring is actually our Guoguang Theater Troupe
春は実は私たちの國光劇団です
just had a play called
という劇があったばかりです
Secret
ひみつ
what is the secret
秘密は何ですか
This play is actually the story of Meng Lijun
この劇は実際には孟立軍の物語です
1993 Yayin Xiaoji by Guo Xiaozhuang
1993年「ヤイン・シャオジ」郭暁荘著
starring Meng Lijun
孟立軍主演
then i think
それから私は思います
This audience friend who may be over 40 years old
この観客の友人はおそらく40歳を超えているでしょう
And the audience friends also know that Guo Xiaozhuang
そして観客の友人も郭暁荘のことを知っています
He himself is a traditional opera
彼自身は伝統的なオペラです
against a rebel
反逆者に対して
So the play is performed by him
それでその劇は彼によって上演される
very suitable
非常に適した
He turns you to sixty-four
彼はあなたを64歳にします
six...six...sixty-four
6...6...64
six minutes and forty seconds
六分四十秒
We started figuring out from six minutes and forty seconds
6分40秒から考え始めた
This paragraph is about the character of Meng Lijun
この段落は孟立軍の人物像についてです。
she is female
彼女は女性です
she posed as a man and got citizenship
彼女は男性のふりをして市民権を獲得した
is burning sun
燃える太陽です
Appears in men's clothing and is in official uniform
紳士服を着て公式制服を着て登場
This is of course a golden sentence
これはもちろん金言です
This is the symbol of masculinity
これは男らしさの象徴です
It is also a symbol of political authority
政治的権威の象徴でもある
good
良い
ok we see here
わかりました、ここでわかります
You can see this Meng Lijun
この孟立軍が見えます
show a smug
表現出一副得意
Yang En is really full of wisdom and virtue
ヤン・エンは本当に知恵と徳に満ちています
OK, let's see a comparison
はい、比較してみましょう
good
良い
On the left is Meng Lijun who wears men's clothing this week
左側は今週紳士服を着た孟立軍です
Miss
逃す
anxiety
心不安
Air
空気
Little Miss
リトル・ミス
red yellow
赤黄
Tokai period
東海時代
red red
赤 赤
anxiety
不安
The one on the right is the emperor
右の人が皇帝です
is his boss
彼の上司です
But what about the boss?
しかし、上司はどうでしょうか？
I saw Meng Lijun's appearance
孟立軍の姿を見ました
Seems
らしい
so what
だから何
Just want to quote Meng Lijun to admit his female identity
孟立軍の言葉を引用して自分の女性であることを認めたいだけです
And become the emperor's neicheng
そして皇帝の姪となる
Well, in the end, of course, the lecherous emperor's trick did not succeed.
まあ、結局のところ、もちろん、好色な皇帝の策略は成功しませんでした。
Meng Lijun is with his fiancé
孟立軍は婚約者と一緒
But is this what Meng Lijun wants?
しかし、これが孟立軍の望みなのだろうか？
Where is this very reluctant emperor?
この非常に消極的な皇帝はどこにいますか？
As a last resort, he must fulfill this Meng Lijun and his fiancée.
最後の手段として、彼はこの孟立軍とその婚約者を満足させなければなりません。
In fact, it is adapted from a work called Rebirth
実はこの作品、Rebirthという作品が原作なんです
Fate of Rebirth actually refers to Meng Lijun and Huangpu Shaohua
「Fate of Rebirth」は実際にはMeng LijunとHuangpu Shaohuaを指します
In fact, they have been married since childhood.
実際、彼らは幼い頃から結婚していました。
The result is that Meng Lijun is so beautiful
その結果、孟立軍はとても美しいです
So there are bad guys who want to
だから、それを望んでいる悪い人たちがいます。
to his fiancé's house
彼の婚約者の家へ
framed
額装された
In this way, you can marry Meng Lijun and go home
このようにして、孟立軍と結婚して家に帰ることができます
Of course, this virtuous and controversial Meng Lijun would not
もちろん、この高潔で物議を醸す孟立軍はそうではないだろう
So he changed Nanzhuang
それで彼は南庄を変えました
Went to Beijing to rush for the exam and won the first prize
北京に行って試験を受けに行き、一等賞を獲得した
Not only that, he also put the world's national
それだけでなく、彼はまた、世界の国家を
Both politics and military affairs are in the hands of the emperor and his own father
政治も軍事も皇帝とその父親の手中にある
and this fiance
そしてこの婚約者
between applause
拍手の間
such a story
そんな話
Then his fiancé
それから彼の婚約者は
In fact, I guessed that the prime minister is a woman
実は首相は女性だったらしい
keep wanting
欲しがり続ける
I begged him to resume women's clothing, but this Meng Lijun was not willing
私は彼に婦人服を再開するよう懇願しましたが、孟立軍はその気はありませんでした。
Because the emperor wanted to bring Meng Lijun into the harem
皇帝は孟立軍をハーレムに迎え入れたかったからです
As a last resort, Meng Lijun finally became Meng Lijun and had to return to women's clothing
最後の手段として、孟立軍は最終的に孟立軍となり、婦人服に戻らなければなりませんでした。
Then in the process
それからその過程で
Meng Lijun was not only unfair to the emperor
孟立軍は皇帝に対して不公平なだけではなかった
Being disobedient to your father is even more disrespectful to your husband
父親に従わないことは夫に対してさらに失礼です
Then this husband because he was originally
では、この夫はもともとそうだったので、
It was under his subordinates that Wu Zhuangyuan passed the exam.
呉荘源が試験に合格したのは彼の部下でした。
Then we know that in traditional times
そうすれば、伝統的な時代には
Teachers and students are very important
先生も生徒もとても大切です
So so his fiancé must also respect him as a teacher
だから彼の婚約者も彼を教師として尊敬しているに違いない
And you have to kneel down to him often, etc.
そして頻繁に彼にひざまずかなければなりません。
then in the novel
それから小説の中で
These episodes are described in great detail.
こういったエピソードが詳しく解説されています。
but must say with joy
しかし、喜びをもって言わなければなりません
And there is a feeling of singing and singing
そして歌って歌う感覚がある
ok so you can imagine
わかりました、想像してみてください
a plot device like this
このようなプロットデバイス
In fact, it is very attractive
実際、それはとても魅力的です
so what
だから何
All genres are successful
どのジャンルも成功している
adapt this story
この物語を改作する
Regardless of what we just saw
私たちが今見たものとは関係なく
Beijing opera is also good
京劇もいいですね
Well actually
まあ実際のところ
Gezai Opera has also been changed
ゲザイオペラも変わりました
It's played by Ye Qing
演じているのはイェ・チンさん
Everyone knows who Ye Qing is, right?
Ye Qingが誰であるかを誰もが知っていますよね?
ok good
いいよ
Gezi Opera also has
ゲジ・オペラには、
Then there are musicals
それからミュージカルもあるよ
Many dramas are like this
こういうドラマ多いよな
Adapted the story of Meng Lijun
孟立軍の物語を脚色
even
平
sorry am i
ごめんなさい、私ですか？
OK I just skipped one
OK、1つスキップしました
even
平
We also saw that he still has rumors overseas
海外ではまだ噂が残っていることも分かりました
can help me point to
指摘するのに役立ちます
Not the place where the manga was adapted
漫画の原作となった場所ではありません
ok let's look at this site
よし、このサイトを見てみよう
This is clearly a Japanese site
これは明らかに日本のサイトです
On this website, he is actually selling
こちらのサイトでは実際に販売しております
cartoon
アニメーション
Let's see this comic
この漫画を見てみよう
what is the story
何の話ですか
new living element
新しい生きた要素
This is Japan in the 21st century
これが21世紀の日本です
Comic creations based on traditional stories
伝統的な物語に基づいた漫画作品
And one of the subjects he chose was in solidarity with
そして彼が選んだ主題の一つは、
we can see inside the cover
カバーの内側が見えます
Meng Lijun this Q version
孟立軍このQバージョン
This image of Meng Lijun
孟立軍のこの画像
we can all see
私たち全員が見ることができます
Such a story of a woman disguised as a man
そんな男装した女の物語
It actually has a rather universal appeal
実はかなり普遍的な魅力を持っているんです
Even cross-cultural still has its appeal
異文化にも魅力はある
ok, what next
わかりました、次は何ですか
Back to PPT
PPTに戻る
next
次
Then let's take a look at this work
それでは、この作品を見てみましょう
what the hell is going on in solidarity
連帯で一体何が起こっているのか
what is its origin
その起源は何ですか
In fact, solidarity is a very typical
実際、連帯感は非常に典型的なものです。
And a classic novel written by a woman
そして女性によって書かれた古典的な小説
then his works
それから彼の作品
Chen Duansheng
チェン・ドゥアンシェン
He was a woman born in the mid-18th century
彼は18世紀半ばに生まれた女性でした。
she wrote this Regeneron
彼女はこのリジェネロンを書きました
It's the story of Meng Lijun we just talked about
先ほど話した孟立軍の話です
Chen Duansheng was born into a very famous literary family
陳端生は非常に有名な文学一家に生まれました。
She followed her grandfather and father as a teenager
彼女は10代の頃、祖父と父親を追った
Mother studies literature and art
母は文学と芸術を勉強しています
From an early age she had to write
幼い頃から彼女は書かなければならなかった
regeneron idea
リジェネロンのアイデア
she started writing
彼女は書き始めた
I will show my mother as I write
書いているところを母に見せます
Share her creative experience with her mother
創造的な経験を母親と共有する
in a year and a half
1年半以内に
She wrote 600,000 words intensively
彼女は集中的に60万語を書きました
I wish I could write my thesis so fast
論文をそんなに早く書けるようになりたいです
She wrote 600,000 words in a year and a half
彼女は1年半で60万語を書きました
Later, because of changes in her family,
その後、家族の変化により、
mother died grandpa died
母が亡くなりました おじいさんが亡くなりました
So she has no interest in writing any more.
したがって、彼女はもう書くことに興味がありません。
This creation is interrupted
この作成は中断されます
then he got married
それから彼は結婚した
Fortunately, he gets along well with her husband.
幸いなことに、彼は夫と仲良くやっています。
It's like living a happy life
まるで幸せな人生を送っているようだ
Unexpectedly, accidental inoculation came
思いがけず、誤接種が来た
His husband was involved in a science factory
彼の夫は科学工場に携わっていた
It's a case of cheating in the exam
試験での不正行為です
We know this in traditional times
伝統的な時代では私たちはこれを知っています
This is Shatou's big case, very serious.
これは沙頭にとって重大な事件であり、非常に深刻です。
then his husband escaped death
その後夫は一命をとりとめた
But he was rushed into the army and exiled
しかし彼は強制徴兵され追放された
Poor Chen Duansheng with two children
2人の子供を持つ貧しいチェン・ドゥアンシェン
was left at home
家に残された
then he had a very, very hard life
それから彼はとてもとても大変な人生を送りました
sad days
悲しい日々
So in his creation from Girls' Generation
だから、少女時代からの彼の作品では
After a 14-year hiatus
14年の休止期間を経て
Chen Duansheng is in this heart
チェン・ドゥアンシェンはこの心の中にいます
in great pain
とても痛い
He decided to recreate
彼は作り直すことに決めた
as a life saver
命の恩人として
He started picking up his pen again
彼は再びペンを持ち始めた
Continue to finish writing the story of Rebirth
再生の物語を書き続ける
but unfortunately
しかし残念ながら
he is still
彼はまだいます
He stopped in the middle of writing
彼は書いている途中でやめた
Then we'll see where he parked later
では、後で彼がどこに駐車したか見てみましょう
he stopped
彼は止まった
Then he himself unfortunately passed away.
その後、彼自身も残念ながら亡くなってしまいました。
Then finally by other female writers
そして最後に他の女性作家による
Helped him finish writing the story of Meng Lijun in Regeneron
『Regeneron』で孟立軍の物語を書き終えるのを手伝った
So this one we just said he wanted to rewrite
それで、これは彼が書き直したいと言っていたところです
But I can't write in one place
でも一か所には書けない
Where can I not write down?
どこに書き込めないのか？
It's exactly the Meng Lijun we saw just now
まさに今見た孟立軍です
His identity is about to be revealed
彼の正体が明らかになりつつある
his dad
彼のお父さん
his fiance and even his emperor
彼の婚約者、そして彼の皇帝さえも
all for different reasons
すべて異なる理由で
oppress him
彼を抑圧する
Hurry up and admit that you are a woman at this critical point
この重要な時点で、急いで自分が女性であることを認めてください
Chen Duansheng stops here
チェン・ドゥアンシェンはここで止まります
We can probably imagine a suffering
おそらく私たちは苦しみを想像できるでしょう
For the plight of women's lives
女性の窮状に向けて
Chen Duansheng with many reflections
多くの反省を持つチェン・ドゥアンシェン
How is he going to end this story?
彼はこの物語をどう終わらせるつもりなのでしょうか？
is following the expectations of most readers
ほとんどの読者の期待に従っています
Like most dramas we have seen
私たちが見てきたほとんどのドラマと同じように
Make Meng Lijun happy
孟立軍を幸せにする
Unload the jade belt and unload the tide view
翡翠のベルトを降ろし、潮の景色を降ろす
Change the beautiful hair of women on the book
本に載っている女性の美しい髪を変える
Put on Jinchai and put on a skirt
ジンチャイを着てスカートを履いて
change back to female
女性に戻ります
can she write like this
彼女はこのように書くことができますか
Or Chen Duansheng in the eighteenth century
あるいは18世紀の陳端生
He might write Meng Lijun as saying
彼は孟立軍に次のように書くかもしれない。
No, I definitely don't want to give up my old political life?
いいえ、私は決して古い政治家人生を放棄したくないのですか？
It seems that Chen Duansheng has no choice
チェン・ドゥアンシェンには選択の余地がないようだ
Choose from either
どちらかをお選びください
Indeed he stops here
確かに彼はここで立ち止まります
The female writer who later helped him finish writing this work
後に彼がこの作品を書き上げるのを手伝った女性作家
Of course it was written with a happy ending
もちろんハッピーエンドで書いてます
What about this work by Chen Dunshen?
チェン・ダンシェンのこの作品はどうでしょうか？
Although he himself did not finish
彼自身は終わっていなかったものの、
But in this Jiangnan area
しかし、この江南地域では
In fact, it is very widespread
実際、非常に普及しているのですが、
It is a situation of manuscripts, manuscripts, manuscripts, and manuscripts being circulated
原稿、原稿、原稿、原稿が出回っている状況です
And his influence is very big
そして彼の影響力は非常に大きいです
At his time and in later generations there were many women writers
彼の時代や後世には女性作家が多かった
respond to his work in different ways
彼の仕事にさまざまな方法で応答する
Well of course we have to stop here
まあ、もちろんここでやめなければなりません
Let's take a look at the form Chen Dunshen used to create
Chen Dunshen が作成したフォームを見てみましょう
If he is writing a novel
もし彼が小説を書いているなら
Why did we not know that women in the Qing Dynasty wrote novels before?
なぜ清朝の女性が小説を書いていたことを私たちはこれまで知らなかったのでしょうか？
That is actually because the novels created by Chen Dunshen have a special form
それは実際、陳敦生の小説が特殊な形式を持っているためです。
He is a person transformed from Tan Ci's performing and rapping form.
彼はTan Ciのパフォーマンスとラップの姿を変えた人物です。
a dark-headed written work
暗い頭で書かれた作品
It's called Tan Ci's novel
タン・チーの小説です
Let's take a closer look
もっと詳しく見てみましょう
so what are the words
それでは、タン語とは何でしょうか？
Simply put, Tan Ci is popular in the Taihu Lake Basin.
端的に言えば、太湖流域で人気があるのがTan Ciです。
Especially Suzhou, today's Shanghai, and so on, a kind of rap art of the generation
特に蘇州、現在の上海など、この世代のラップアートの一種
This kind of rap art is mixed
こういうラップアートが混じってる
just sing in rhyme
ただ韻を踏んで歌うだけ
but also uses some prose to tell part of the story
ただし、ストーリーの一部を伝えるために散文も使用します
Sanxian and pipa are used to accompany the performance
演奏の伴奏には三仙と琵琶が使用されます。
Then the style of Tan Ci is very delicate, soft, and even sleepy.
そして、Tan Ciのスタイルは非常に繊細で柔らかく、そして眠たくさえあります。
So it is still a very popular art form today.
したがって、それは今日でも非常に人気のある芸術形式です。
And Tan Ci novels are many women who love this art form
そして、Tan Ci の小説には、この芸術形式を愛する多くの女性がいます。
transformed into a form of writing
文章の形に変換される
Well, maybe not everyone here has heard what Tanci is
まあ、ここにいる誰もが Tanci が何であるかを聞いたことがあるわけではないかもしれません
So I took a very old route from decades ago
だから私は何十年も前の非常に古い道をたどりました
Let everyone know what is marble
大理石とは何かをみんなに知ってもらうために
wait a minute
先等一下
Let's take a look at this picture in the upper left corner
この左上の画面を見てみましょう
This is the form of the manuscript of Tanci novels
これはタンシ小説の原稿の形式です
These works are often in the form of manuscript transcripts
これらの作品は多くの場合、原稿転写の形式で作成されます。
published after a long time
久しぶりに公開されました
Then the performance form of Tanci is like
では、タンチのパフォーマンスフォームは次のようになります
This image we see in the lower left corner
この画像は左下隅に表示されます
There will be one person or two people
1人か2人になります
Perform with a stringed instrument
弦楽器を使って演奏する
But you should pay attention
でも注意したほうがいいよ
In fact, in the traditional era
実は伝統的な時代には
Those who can go to the stage to perform Tanci
舞台に上がってタンシを演じられる方
absolutely not
絶対違う
they must be men
彼らは男性に違いない
Only men can go to the bookstore to perform
本屋に行ってパフォーマンスできるのは男性だけ
Women can only go inside the house at most
女性はせいぜい家の中にしか入れない
to perform in a private venue
プライベートな会場で演奏する
good
良い
Then let's take a look at a short
それでは、短いものを見てみましょう
this
これ
an older video
古いビデオ
What about this paragraph?
この段落はどうでしょうか？
It's a lady talking to a maid
メイドと話している女性です
Maid ran over
メイドさんが駆け寄りました
no it's another
いいえ、それは別です
The maid ran over and reported to the lady that
メイドは駆け寄り、お嬢様にこう報告した。
Your fiancé is here, go out and see
あなたの婚約者がここにいます、外に出て見てください
But what about this maid, he didn't directly say
でもこのメイドはどうしたの、彼は直接は言わなかった
He deliberately teased this lady
彼は意図的にこの女性をからかった
gossip
ゴシップ
This funny lady is angry and funny
この面白い女性は怒っていて面白いです
I'm sorry
ごめんなさい
So according to their conversation
それで、彼らの会話によれば、
we can see the performance of this korean word
この韓国語の単語のパフォーマンスがわかります
So yes, it has both dramatic tension and lingering
そう、劇的な緊張感と余韻の両方を持っています。
Official Jade Flag
公式翡翠旗
Wow
おお
you hurry up and send it again
急いでもう一度送ってください
Whoosh, go feed yourself
うーん、自分で食べてください
you go kick it
あなたはそれを蹴りに行きます
post it
投稿してください
hello it
こんにちは。
stranger it
見知らぬ人
because tactics step it up
戦術がさらに強化するから
Haha good area
はは、良いエリア
who wants to send it
送りたい人は
nibbling
かじる
say it
それを言う
i want without it too
それなしも欲しいです
it's one of you girls here it is
それはあなたの女の子の一人です、ここにいます
I dust wash my aunt
私は叔母をほこり洗いします
Not many sighed loose powder
ため息のルースパウダーが少ない
fresh girl holes it
新鮮な女の子はそれを穴にします
"!
”！
Then thank you for teaching me to move you
それでは、あなたを動かす方法を教えてくれてありがとう
Listen to individual words
個々の言葉を聞く
Thank you for your teaching and forgive him
教えてくれてありがとう、そして彼を許してください
a parte
ダービーがパートを作る
That one is more self-satisfied than he does not move tiy
動かないより自己満足だよ
i don't listen to her
彼女の言うことを聞かない
legs
足
choose her
彼女を選んでください
ditch
溝
It's not appropriate to say it's all a secret
すべてが秘密だというのは適切ではない
the main kid
メインの子供
you are the wind of flowers
あなたは花の風です
have to do
しなければなりません
very nice
非常に素晴らしい
Said it was all hard work
全部大変だったって言ってた
Miss threatened that you are here and I will beat you
ミスは、あなたがここにいると私があなたを殴ると脅しました
Miss said you want to call
嬢が電話したいって言ってた
Okay, then we can see this Tanci performance
よし、それではタンチのパフォーマンスを見てみよう
It's actually very dramatic.
実はとてもドラマチックなんです。
We can't imagine with our present eyes
今の私たちの目では想像できない
You're putting yourself in an eighteenth century
あなたは自分自身を18世紀に置いているのです
Women who returned to China in the depths of the 19th century
19世紀末に中国に帰国した女性たち
if you see a show like this
こんな番組を見たら
you will actually be touched
あなたは感動するでしょう
And it's really going to be fun, right?
そしてそれは本当に楽しいことになるでしょう?
Well, if you still remember that Dream of the Red Chamber was in the very front
そう、赤い部屋の夢が一番前にあったことをまだ覚えているなら
Isn't Jam talking to a so-called fairy girl?
ジャムはいわゆる妖精の女の子と話しているのではありませんか？
They invited this female performer to their home
彼らはこの女性パフォーマーを自宅に招待しました
Are you here to perform?
パフォーマンスするためにここにいますか？
Then the fairy girl said
すると妖精の女の子は言いました。
Otherwise, I will sing the story of Fengqiu Huang
そうでなければ、私は黄鳳丘の物語を歌います
remember
覚えて
So that performance should actually be something like ours
つまり、そのパフォーマンスは実際には私たちのものに似ているはずです
I saw such a performance of Tanci
そんなタンチのパフォーマンスを見ました
So we can actually imagine
それで私たちは実際に想像することができます
At that time, there were quite a few returned women.
当時は帰国した女性も多かったです。
will be rewarded for seeing such a performance
あんなパフォーマンスを見たら報われるだろう
Attract some of these women who are educated to write
書く教育を受けた女性たちを惹きつける
She thought I could use this format to create a story
彼女は私がこのフォーマットを使って物語を作れると思ったのです
We know that storytelling is actually a human instinct
私たちはストーリーテリングが実際には人間の本能であることを知っています
Especially women love to tell stories
特に女性は物語が大好きです
So that's how the novel of talking words came about.
こうして、言葉を話す小説が生まれたのです。
And compared to the performance of talking words in the performance we just watched
そしてさっき観た公演での言葉を話すパフォーマンスと比べて
There will be more textual parts in real talk novels
リアルトーク小説ではテキスト部分が増えます
The design of the characters The description of the characters will be more detailed and the plot will be very complicated
キャラクターのデザイン キャラクターの説明がより詳細になり、プロットが非常に複雑になります
Just like Zhang Hui’s novels like Dream of the Red Chamber and Oil Absorbent that we usually see
私たちがよく目にする張輝の小説『紅楼夢』や『油吸収剤』と同じように、
It must also have Zhang, Huihui, Huimei, etc., which have all the necessary conditions for novels
また、Zhang、Huihui、Huimei など、小説に必要な条件をすべて備えている必要があります。
The structure is also very complete
構造も非常に完成度が高い
But it will use seven fonts
ただし、7 つのフォントが使用されます
tell stories in english
英語で物語を語る
Therefore
したがって
So when we take the concept of the so-called novel
したがって、いわゆる小説の概念を取り上げると、
Fixed in the so-called vernacular Zhang Hui novels
いわゆる張輝の俗小説で修正されたもの
Then there is no place for this novel
そうなるとこの小説の居場所はない
so that's why
だから
This is what we've been taught since childhood
これは私たちが子供の頃から教えられてきたことです
in the education of literature
文学教育において
no one told us
誰も私たちに教えてくれなかった
It turns out that women in the Qing Dynasty wrote novels
清朝の女性が小説を書いていたことが判明
called talking about this novel
この小説について話すという電話がかかってきた
So
それで
maybe you want to ask
もしかしたら聞きたいかもしれません
Are there any Zhang Hui novels written by women in vernacular?
女性が現地語で書いた張輝の小説はありますか?
Actually not without
実際にはそれがないわけではありません
At least we know that in the second half of the nineteenth century
少なくとも私たちが知っているのは、19世紀後半には
There is an aristocratic woman named Gu Taiqing
顧太清という名の貴族の女性がいる
she actually wrote a
彼女は実際にこう書きました
The narrative book of Dream of Red Mansions is called Dream of Red Mansions
紅楼夢の物語本は『紅楼夢』と呼ばれています。
shadow of shadow
影の影
But this is a very special case
しかし、これは非常に特殊なケースです
What about women writing Zhang Hui's novels?
張輝の小説を書く女性についてはどうですか？
almost unique
ほぼユニークな
Then this Dream of the Red Chamber is probably
ならばこの赤い部屋の夢はおそらく
is a rare example
珍しい例です
And in contrast
そしてそれとは対照的に
What about Tanci novels?
タンチの小説はどうですか？
There are quite a lot of women to create
作る女性はかなり多い
You can count more than ten or twenty kinds by random counting.
ランダムに数えると10種類、20種類以上数えることができます。
then we're going to ask
それから私たちは尋ねます
Why Women Don't Write Zhang Hui's Novels in Vernacular
なぜ女性は張輝の小説を現地語で書かないのか
And choose this form of Tanci to write novels?
そして、小説を書くためにこの形式のタンシを選択しますか？
Of course, there is no standard answer to this.
もちろん、これに対する標準的な答えはありません。
I can only make some guesses
ある程度の推測しかできません
So first of all what we just said
まず第一に、今言ったこと
Because the performance of Tanci has a kind of attraction
タンチのパフォーマンスにはある種の魅力があるから
then women like to hear
それから女性は聞くのが好きです
Then it's natural to say
それならこう言うのが自然だ
I use this form to create
このフォームを使用して作成します
Other women may also like to watch
他の女性も見たいかもしれません
right
右
So this could be a
したがって、これは次の可能性があります
The psychology of expecting other women to enjoy reading
他の女性が読書を楽しんでくれることを期待する心理
this is one of them
これはそのうちの 1 つです
i think one of the reasons
理由の一つだと思う
Another reason?
もう一つの理由？
Tanci itself is a kind of entertainment
Tanci 自体は一種のエンターテイメントです
it is unrefined
それは洗練されていない
What about this male literati?
この男性文人はどうでしょうか？
for
ために
It is simply dismissive of women to write in this form
このような形式で書くことは女性を軽視しているだけです
That is to say, I will not read it at all.
つまり、全く読まないのです。
won't go to see
見に行きません
so is that a good thing or a bad thing
それで、それは良いことですか、それとも悪いことですか
hard to say right?
言いにくいですよね？
It's a bad thing because it doesn't get more attention
もっと注目されないからダメなんだよ
but it's a good thing
でもそれは良いことだ
Because he left a lot of room for these women to run wild horses
なぜなら、彼は女性たちが野生の馬を走らせるための余地をたくさん残していたからです。
If we carefully read the thoughts written by these women
彼女たちの書いた思いをよく読んでみると、
say what we will see
私たちが見ることになるものを言う
This language is really when writing talk novels
トーク小説を書くときはまさにこの言語です
It can get rid of many talented women and the like
有能な女性などを大量に排除できる
many of them in other forms such as poetry
それらの多くは詩など他の形式で書かれています
For example, emotions that are inconvenient to write in words
たとえば、言葉にするには不便な感情
ambivalence or even desire etc.
両価性や欲望など。
or some really wild imagination
あるいは本当にワイルドな想像力
It can all be written in the form of talkative novels
それはすべて饒舌な小説の形で書くことができます
and get letters from other women
他の女性から手紙を受け取る
Standards and norms of mainstream society that loves men without offending them
男性を傷つけることなく愛する主流社会の基準と規範
This is another possible reason I think
これも考えられるもう一つの理由だと思います
So anyway what I have to point out here is that
とにかく、ここで私が指摘しなければならないのは、
Whether it is Li Qingzhao in the Song Dynasty or the female writers in the Ming and Qing Dynasties
宋の李青照にしても、明清の女流作家にしても
Or the female novelists of the Qing Dynasty like Chen Duansheng we have seen here
あるいは、ここで見た陳端生のような清朝の女性小説家たち
Writing is a creative activity for them
彼らにとって書くことは創造的な活動です
is a way of pursuing an immortal possibility for oneself
それは自分自身の不滅の可能性を追求する方法です
We all know that Confucianism says that there are ways to pursue immortality in life.
私たちは皆、儒教が生命の不滅を追求する方法があると言っていることを知っています。
Three Immortals
三不朽
Thank you Lide for your meritorious service
リドさんの功績に感謝します
So what can we do to build morality for women?
では、女性の道徳性を高めるために何ができるでしょうか?
If the husband is not dead, he can't be robbed quickly, right?
旦那が死んでなかったらすぐに強盗に遭わないですよね？
If meritorious service cannot go to the public domain
功績がパブリックドメインに移せない場合
how do you do meritorious service
どうやって功労を立てるのか
The only thing to say is that it is locked in the defense
ただ一つ言えるのは守備に固まっているということ
It is also possible to engage in a creative activity
創作活動も可能です
Then women pursue this kind of
すると女性はこの種のことを追求します
After you can let your own body go to ashes
自分の体を灰に帰してから
It is also possible to exist in pursuit of immortality
不死を求めて存在することも可能
such a way
そんな方法で
Well, this is a common ultimate pursuit of human beings
まあ、これは人間の共通の究極の追求です
Then the so-called talented women are not ignorant
そうすると、いわゆる優秀な女性は無知ではないのです
Awareness of unwillingness to sleep
眠りたくないという意識
It was born from such an impulse to pursue immortality.
そんな不死を追求する衝動から生まれました。
good
良い
Then I think we might as well come together
それなら一緒に来てもいいと思うよ
Look at the text of the section inside the solidarity
連帯内のセクションのテキストを見てください。
So just now we introduced the author who is in solidarity
さて、先ほど連帯する著者を紹介しました
Chen Duansheng
チェン・ドゥアンシェン
then we also know
それなら私たちも知っています
different from current writers
今の作家とは違う
Today's novelists, of course
もちろん現代の小説家も
I went everywhere to type books
私は本を​​タイプするためにどこへでも行きました
But the novelists of the classical age
しかし、古典時代の小説家たちは、
In fact, I am very conscious of what I write
実際、私は自分が何を書いているかを非常に意識しています
is an art called trail
それはトレイルという芸術です
It's not in the hall of the big government
大きな政府の広間にはない
So even male authors
だから男性作家でも
are often reluctant to disclose their identities
多くの場合、自分の身元を明らかにすることに消極的です
Well, let alone women
まあ、女性はもちろんのこと、
And for Chen Duansheng
そしてチェン・ドゥアンシェンさんへ
He's still a sinner's wife
彼はまだ罪人の妻です
right
右
We just said his husband was exiled
彼の夫が追放されたと言いました
So even though he is a comedian from a famous family
名家のコメディアンなのに
But our whole background about Chen Duansheng
しかし、チェン・ドゥアンシェンに関する私たちの背景全体
Actually don't know much
実はあまり知らない
So how do we know there is a protozoa?
では、原生動物の存在はどのようにしてわかるのでしょうか?
Written by this woman named Chen Duansheng
チェン・ドゥアンシェンという女性が書いたもの
He will never be like a modern writer
彼は決して現代の作家のようにはならないだろう
He mentioned his name on the fertilizer industry
肥料業界で名前を挙げた人
how did you do it
どうやってやったの？
how do we know
どうやって知ることができますか
That's because the author
それは作者が
He will use a form of speech
彼はあるスピーチ形式を使うだろう
And at the beginning of each chapter
そして各章の冒頭には
or
また
Going to write a long paragraph at the end has nothing to do with the storyline
最後に長い文章を書くのはストーリーラインとは何の関係もありません
But with his own current feeling
でも彼自身の今の気持ちとしては
or seasons or circumstances or experiences
季節や状況や経験
Or words related to his mood
または彼の気分に関連した言葉
Then we can see from this paragraph
この段落からわかるように、
This paragraph is the beginning of volume 17
この段落は17巻の冒頭です
Volume 17 is exactly what Chen Duansheng wrote in his
第 17 巻はまさに、Chen Duansheng が著書で書いた内容です。
14 years off
14年間の休暇
After he has gone through all kinds of hardships in life
彼は人生であらゆる種類の困難を経験した後、
the volume that started writing again
再び書き始めた巻
Let's see him at the beginning of this volume
この巻の冒頭で彼に会いましょう
how to describe yourself
自分自身をどのように説明するか
Then please read the text on the PPT directly
次に、PPT のテキストを直接読んでください。
then he said
それから彼は言いました
What about him
彼についてはどうですか
Shaking my head to ask God
頭を振って神に尋ねる
Why is the law of heaven so unfair?
なぜ天の法則はこれほど不公平なのでしょうか？
ask the sky
空に尋ねてください
he is here
彼はここにいます
In fact, it is a rhetoric that follows Chu Ci Tianwen from afar
実際、これは朱慈天文を遠くから追随するレトリックです
Yeah
うん
express a
ある種のことを表現する
a sorrow of life
人生の悲しみ
He said I've grown out of all the troubles in the world
彼は私が世界中のあらゆる困難から抜け出して成長したと言いました
So I miss returning to the center even more
だからセンターに戻るのがさらに恋しい
when young
若い頃
that carefree era
あの気ままな時代
what did he do at that time
彼はその時何をしましたか
He said me and my sister
彼は私と私の妹を言いました
sleep together
一緒に寝る
Let's listen to the sound of rain at night
夜の雨の音を聞こう
Mom and Dad teach us to do our homework
お父さんとお母さんは私たちに宿題をするように教えます
teach us how to make poetry
詩の作り方を教えてください
This is what parents teach their daughters to write poetry
これは親が娘に詩を書くように教えることです
This is the cultivation of talented women in Ming and Qing Dynasties
これは明清時代の優秀な女性の育成です
a very common situation
非常に一般的な状況
In other words, although they don't necessarily go to school
つまり、必ずしも学校に通っているわけではないのですが、
But they can learn from family education
しかし、彼らは家庭教育から学ぶことができます
get artistic training
芸術的な訓練を受ける
Next he said when I was young
次に彼は私が若い頃こう言いました。
Follow my father out to be an official
父を追って役人になる
Then I have experienced many mountains and rivers
それから私はたくさんの山や川を経験しました
what about father
お父さんはどうですか
My parents love me very much
両親は私をとても愛しています
Although in my literature and art
私の文学や芸術においては
There is no way to talk to this kind of rich girl who has not entered the era
こんな時代に入っていない金持ち娘に話しかけるわけがない
For example, who is Everlasting Wealth?
たとえば、永遠の富とは誰でしょうか？
Xie Daoyun
謝道雲
I can't talk to Xie Daoyun
謝道雲さんとは話せない
Or another rich woman who wrote flowers to send
あるいは別の裕福な女性が花を書いて送った
This Ms. Chen
このチェンさんは
compared to
に比べ
but
しかし
He said I can't compare
彼は「比べられない」と言った
In fact, I want to compare
実際に比べてみたい
Do you guys know this rhetoric?
皆さんはこのレトリックを知っていますか？
Fama
ファマ
OK
OK
Although I am not as good as them
私は彼らほど上手ではありませんが、
And what?
そして何？
The tube system in my pen is my pen
私のペンのチューブシステムは私のペンです
Do I dare to write the eternal things in my pen?
永遠のものをあえてペンで書くだろうか？
do i dare to go
あえて行ってみますか
Just like Li Qingzhao we mentioned earlier
先ほど述べた李青照のように
to reflect on history?
歴史を振り返るには？
Oh I dare not
ああ、あえてしない
I don't dare to say it, but I really want it
あえて言えないけど本当に欲しい
then what do i dare to do
それなら私はあえて何をしますか
Haoduan writes in solidarity
ハオドゥアン氏は連帯を表明する
then we see here
それからここを見ます
he used a small word
他用了一個細字
This fine print is true on the one hand
この細かい点は一方では真実です
because he was a child
彼は子供だったから
he is a teenager
彼は十代の若者です
writing seemed to him
彼には書くことがそう見えた
yes it's a game
はい、それはゲームです
But on the other hand this fine
しかし一方で、これは大丈夫です
Too
それも
It is a kind of original intention of creation
それはある種の創作意図です
without any power
何の力もなしに
i just want to write
ただ書きたいだけです
i just want to create
ただ作りたいだけです
I just wanna make up a story
ただ物語を作りたいだけなの
Then Cheng Duansheng at this time is very lucky
そうすると、この時のチェン・ドゥアンシェンは非常に幸運です
Because my loving mother saw what I wrote
愛する母が私が書いたものを見たから
Will smile lovingly to teach me
優しく微笑んで教えてくれる
what should be done
何をすべきか
Then I eat children
それから私は子供たちを食べます
My silly daughter is by my mother's side
愚かな娘は母の側にいる
I told her my dreams
私は彼女に自分の夢を話しました
But since my mother died
でも母が亡くなってからは
I am no longer in the mood to write
もう書く気力がなくなった
I put down my pen
私はペンを置きました
Then I omitted a large part in the middle
それから真ん中の大きな部分を省略しました
It's really very long
本当にとても長いです
and after
以降
I went back to my hometown with my family
家族と一緒に故郷に帰りました
It's the boat that goes back home
家に帰る船です
the boat goes very slowly
ボートはとてもゆっくり進みます
So I have a lot of time to waste
だから無駄にする時間がたくさんあるんだ
then what should we do
じゃあどうすればいいのか
I will take out the manuscript of my novel
小説の原稿を取り出します
I wonder if I can write again
また書けるかな
Born to be a leisurely man, if I have nothing to do, I will write again
暇人に生まれて何もすることがなかったらまた書きます
At this time, in fact, I have misled some religious truths.
実はこの時、私はいくつかの宗教的真実を誤解させてきました。
Which means I don't want to follow the right path in life.
つまり、人生において正しい道を歩みたくないのです。
What is the right way, what is the right way for women
何が正しい道なのか、女性にとって正しい道とは何か
That is, you want to be a daughter, a father, and a mother, right?
それは、娘になりたい、父親になりたい、母親になりたい、ということですよね？
He said I don't want 'cause I misled some zen
彼は、私が禅を誤解させたので、それは望まないと言いました
Then everyone should pay attention to the fact that in the Ming and Qing Dynasties, the pursuit of religion
それでは、明と清の時代には宗教の追求が行われていたという事実に誰もが注意を払う必要があります。
also become a very very important one for women
女性にとっても非常に重要なものになります
The so-called ultimate pursuit is to surpass oneself
いわゆる究極の追求は自分を超えること
A way of gender limiting
性別を制限する方法
Well, Chen Duansheng also said the same thing, it's a pity that Ke Nai is still in the vulgar world
まあ、チェン・ドゥアンシェンも同じことを言いました、ケ・ナイがまだ下品な世界にいるのは残念です
At this time, he has no way to break through absolutely
現時点では絶対に突破する術はない
The so-called right way of life for women, this life plan added to him
いわゆる女性の正しい生き方、この人生設計が彼に加わった
So he's still married. After marriage, it's just like vulgarity.
それで彼はまだ結婚していますが、結婚後は下品のようなものです。
here we see marriage is what we see here
ここで私たちが見ているのは結婚です
A Life of All the Women Writers
すべての女性作家の生涯
turning point
転換点
However, Chen Duansheng was very lucky at the beginning
しかし、チェン・ドゥアンシェンは最初は非常に幸運でした
He said my Wengu was good to me
彼は私のウェングが私に良くしてくれたと言った
my husband is a confidant
私の夫は親友です
We light up and half read
点灯して半分読みます
On the one hand, he is in charge of checking, and on the other hand, I accompany him to study.
彼はチェックを担当する一方で、私は彼の勉強に同行します。
Not only that, we also remind teachers
それだけでなく、教師にも注意を促します
Burn out the candle
ろうそくの火を消してください
Let's compete who can do things faster
誰が早くできるかを競いましょう
we can imagine how
どのようにして私たちは想像できるでしょうか
A happy homely couple
幸せな家庭的なカップル
Of course, this should also remind us of
もちろん、これは私たちに次のことを思い出させる必要があります
The relationship between Li Qingzhao and Zhao Mingcheng
李青照と趙明成の関係
This is a so-called
これはいわゆる
contemporary scholars call it
現代の学者はそれをこう呼んでいます
A relationship of partner marriage
パートナーとの結婚関係
That is to say, in the traditional marriage system,
つまり、伝統的な結婚制度では、
Originally between the couple
もともと夫婦の間で
Seems like there's only one kind of family obligation
どうやら家族の義務は1種類だけのようだ
But what about partner marriages?
しかし、パートナーの結婚についてはどうでしょうか？
But it can create a kind of mutual understanding between couples
しかし、それはカップルの間にある種の相互理解を生み出すことができます
not only have feelings
感情があるだけではなく
And this cultural exchange
そしてこの文化交流
this way of marriage
この結婚のやり方
Therefore, Chengzhuan students in this period
したがって、この時代の成莊の学生は、
Not only a successful marriage
結婚生活がうまくいくだけではない
And there are descendants
そして子孫もいる
for him at this time
この時の彼にとって
It's really the end of life
本当に人生の終わりだ
It's a pity that his husband was forced by the so-called force
彼の夫がいわゆる暴力によって強制されたのは残念です
Minjiang is asking Ke Ming
閔江氏は柯明氏に尋ねている
to pursue a career
キャリアを追求する
and apparently committed a crime
そして明らかに犯罪を犯した
It's the section chief's fraud case.
まさに課長の詐欺事件です。
he can't say here
彼はここでは言えません
because the first aspect is embarrassing
最初の面が恥ずかしいから
The second aspect we just said
先ほど述べた 2 番目の側面
The section chief's case is a major case, Shatou's crime
課長の事件は大事件、沙頭の犯罪
Therefore, Chengzhuan is not obvious
したがって、Chengzhuanは明らかではありません
then the end is
それで終わりは
Here he uses two images
ここで彼は 2 つの画像を使用しています
One is to break the suspicion and the other is to break the ban
1 つは疑惑を解くこと、もう 1 つは禁止を破ることです
Of course both point to a broken marriage
もちろんどちらも結婚生活の破綻を示唆している
symbol of an unhappy marriage
不幸な結婚生活の象徴
Then under his husband is another
それから彼の夫の下に別の人がいます
He didn't say it directly but we could read it
彼は直接それを言ったわけではないが、私たちはそれを読み取ることができた
Group eyes open outside the setting sun
夕日の外でグループの目を開ける
His husband was exiled far away
彼の夫は遠くに追放された
no longer with this family
もうこの家族とはいない
And it's one of the sidelines
そしてそれは副業の一つです
sad exile
悲しい追放
What about Chen Duansheng?
チェン・ドゥアンシェンはどうですか？
Of course he's been sad ever since
もちろん彼はそれ以来ずっと悲しんでいました
This mark is messed up
このマークはめちゃくちゃです
He said that for many years
彼は何年もそう言ってた
He is in a state of extreme distress
彼は極度の苦痛の状態にある
What about him, there is no way to reciprocate
彼はどうですか、見返す方法はありません
The relationship between his husband and him
夫と彼との関係
he can only watch
彼はただ見守ることしかできない
His two sons and daughters worked hard to survive
彼の2人の息子と娘は生き残るために懸命に働いた
then he said for him
それから彼は彼のために言いました
this home he lives in
彼が住んでいるこの家
like a castle
城のように
lock him in
彼を閉じ込める
Let him be a hatred
彼を憎しみの対象にしましょう
Although he wants to fly to her husband's side
夫の元へ飛んで行きたいのに
But there's no African American, right?
でもアフリカ系アメリカ人はいないですよね？
There is nothing he can do about Fengyan
鳳燕に関しては何も出来ない
reunited with his husband
夫と再会した
You see we read from this text
このテキストからわかるように、
We can probably see that Chen Duansheng narrated
おそらくChen Duanshengがナレーションを行っていることがわかります。
he grew up
彼は育った
This literary training in the rules
ルールに基づいたこの文学的訓練
The practice of literature and art between parents and sisters
両親と姉妹の間での文学と芸術の実践
life after marriage
結婚後の生活
his relationship with his husband
彼の夫との関係
misfortune suffered by his husband
夫が受けた不幸
and his own fate
そして彼自身の運命
Is it all written in this paragraph?
この段落に全部書いてありますか？
So this master of the twentieth century, Mr. Chen Yingque
この20世紀の巨匠、陳英歌氏です。
He will be able to follow the clues here
彼はここで手がかりをたどることができるだろう
To compare some other historical records of the Qing Dynasty
清朝の他のいくつかの歴史的記録を比較するには
to compare
比べる
And finally came to this conclusion
そして最終的にこの結論に達しました
is the author of Regenerated Source
『Regenerated Source』の著者です
It's Chen Duansheng
チェン・ドゥアンシェン
Then such a form of creation
そして、そのような創造の形
We can see that
それがわかります
this is the author
これが著者です
He is writing a novel on the one hand
彼は一方で小説を書いている
But on the one hand he is writing about himself
しかし一方では彼は自分自身について書いている
He couldn't help but write himself in
彼は自分のことを書かずにはいられなかった
Because he was really afraid of writing it himself
彼は自分で書くのが本当に怖かったから
Just this area of ​​flesh and blood is invincible with the disappearance of his life
この血肉の領域だけは彼の命の消滅とともに無敵である
I think it's a very, very deep kind of fear
それはとてもとても深い恐怖だと思う
because of this fear
この恐怖のせいで
So these women have an urge to create
ですから、これらの女性たちは何かを作りたいという衝動を持っています。
We just said that the previous part of this regeneration source
この再生ソースの前の部分は、
That is to say, the first sixteen volumes were written by this Chen Duansheng when he was a young girl
つまり、最初の 16 巻は、この陳端生が若い頃に書いたものです。
The order of this section of the seventeenth volume has a
第 17 巻のこのセクションの順序は次のとおりです。
Looking at the role of experience in the first half of your life
人生の前半における経験の役割を考える
The cultivation of this talented woman she described here
彼女がここで説明したこの才能ある女性の育成について
and their married life
そして彼らの結婚生活
In fact, among the talented women of Ming and Qing Dynasties, they are quite representative.
実際、明と清の時代の才能ある女性の中でも、彼女たちは非常に代表的な女性です。
We can also see Chen Duansheng here
ここでもチェン・ドゥアンシェンを見ることができます
His entire narrative voice changed
彼のナレーションの声全体が変わった
Because you only see this part, so you can't feel it
この段落しか見てないから感じられないから
If we read from the first volume
1巻から読むと
we will clearly see
私たちははっきりと見るでしょう
Chen Duansheng the author
著者の陳端生
when he was the narrator
彼がナレーターだったとき
His tone changed completely
彼の口調は完全に変わった
from a clueless
無知な者から
very happy to write
書くことができてとても嬉しいです
just for the game
ゲームのためだけに
Just to make mom happy like this one
こうやってママを幸せにするためだけに
innocent girl
無邪気な女の子
transformed into a person who experienced Tibet
チベットを体験した人に変身
And one who is very dissatisfied with society
そして社会に対して強い不満を持っている人
middle-aged woman
中年女性
An image of a woman who has experienced Tibet
チベットを体験した女性のイメージ
So
それで
He can no longer use a kind of tenderness
彼はもう優しさのようなものを使うことができない
or the attitude of the game
あるいはゲームに対する姿勢
To face this fate of women
女性の運命に立ち向かうために
good
良い
Then we can see here
それではここでご覧いただけます
What about Tan Ci's novels?
タン・チーの小説はどうですか？
he has a lot of space in him
彼の中にはたくさんのスペースがある
What about the women of the Ming and Qing Dynasties?
明や清の時代の女性はどうだったのでしょうか？
can express one's true self
本当の自分を表現できる
Next, let's take a look at the development centered on this Regeneron.
次に、このリジェネロンを中心とした展開を見てみましょう。
A whole series of romance novels about love for women
女性向けの愛を描いたロマンス小説シリーズ
Regeneron, we are the first to talk about it is definitely not without reason
リジェネロン、私たちはそれが間違いなく理由がないわけではないことについて最初に話します
because it is a true classic of women's love fiction
それは女性のラブストーリーの真の古典だからです
Not only is the work itself complete, but the plot and characters are designed
作品自体が完成しているだけでなく、プロットやキャラクターもデザインされている
are very attractive
とても魅力的です
It also has topics that many women will find interesting
多くの女性が興味を持ちそうな話題も満載です
So centered on Regeneron we can see that there is a network of text
Regeneron を中心として、テキストのネットワークがあることがわかります。
a web with a text
テキストのあるウェブ
In this web we can see female narrative literature
このウェブでは女性の物語文学を見ることができます
A Development Track of Women's Novels
女性向け小説の発展の軌跡
There are several key points in this track
このトラックにはいくつかの重要なポイントがあります
what are the key points
重要なポイントは何ですか
First, women are going out into the public domain
第一に、女性は公の場に進出しつつある
The second is to establish a personal public enterprise, a personal industry
第二に、個人的な公共企業、個人的な産業を設立することです。
The third is to explore the multiple possibilities of women's feelings and even friendship
3つ目は、女性の感情や友情のさまざまな可能性を探ることです。
Fourth, we must pursue the ultimate meaning of human life
第四に、私たちは人間の人生の究極の意味を追求しなければなりません
These key points will be included in these many works
これらの重要なポイントは、これらの多くの作品に含まれます
constantly being repeated and performed
常に繰り返され実行される
Of course, these are works of the Qing Dynasty
もちろん清代の作品です
So it has the limitations of its age
だから、年齢による限界がある
So we said just now that there is a prerequisite for going out and establishing a public company
したがって、先ほど私たちは、株式公開会社を設立するには前提条件があると言いました。
It's just that it doesn't do these things as a woman
ただ、女性としてこういったことはしないのです
It has to be like what we just saw
それは私たちが今見たものと同じでなければなりません
Meng Lijun from the small country village, right?
孟立軍はあの小さな田舎の村出身ですよね？
it must be dressed as a male
それは男装しなければならない
with a masculine mask after wearing a masculine mask
男性的なマスクを着用した後、男性的なマスクを付けて
He was able to get out of the boudoir, he was able to build an industry
彼は私室から出ることができ、産業を築くことができた
He is able to pursue lust and so on
彼は欲望などを追求することができる
These are a necessary design
これらは必要なデザインです
So what you see on the screen
それで、画面に表示されるものは
Almost all works involve a key to the plot
ほぼ全ての作品にストーリーの鍵がかかっている
it's called crossdressing
それは女装と呼ばれます
and as we have just said
そして今言ったように
The Female Writers of the Ming and Qing Dynasties
明・清時代の女流作家たち
There is a big difference between them and the female writers of the Song Dynasty
宋代の女流作家たちとは大きな違いがある
That is, women in the Ming and Qing Dynasties would actively pursue a sense of community
つまり、明と清の時代の女性は積極的に共同体意識を追求したのです。
No matter the community is our whole family girls can write
コミュニティが家族全員であっても、女の子は書くことができます
Or the female literary talents in our Huxiang area are very powerful
あるいは、私たちの湖郷地域の女性の文学的才能は非常に強力です
Or our talented women in Hangzhou are very powerful, etc.
あるいは、杭州の才能ある女性は非常に強力である、などです。
They will pursue a sense of community
彼らは共同体感覚を追求するだろう
This is of course for our contemporary
もちろんこれは現代の私たちにとっても
We are all so familiar with community culture in modern times
私たちは現代のコミュニティ文化にとても慣れています
For example, we are now live
たとえば、私たちは今ライブ中です
Maybe everyone who is watching the live broadcast
もしかしたら生放送をご覧の皆様も
feel that they are in the same
彼らは同じだと感じます
In the same field even though we are far apart
遠く離れていても同じフィールドで
So this feeling is actually
だからこの気持ちは実は
Women in the Ming and Qing Dynasties were also pursuing
明・清の時代の女性たちも追求していた
So how do they pursue
では、彼らはどのように追求するのでしょうか
They certainly don't have modern technology
彼らは確かに現代のテクノロジーを持っていません
But what, they can text
でもなんと、彼らはテキストメッセージを送信できるのです
they will text
彼らはテキストメッセージを送ります
and responses to the text to create this sense of community
コミュニティの感覚を生み出すためのテキストへの返信
This is a literary community
ここは文学コミュニティです
Then the renewable source is such a kind
再生可能エネルギー源とはそのようなものです
A center for an imaginative literary community
想像力豊かな文学コミュニティのセンター
Then we can probably see
そうすればおそらく見えるでしょう
In fact, the source of reproduction is not an isolated work.
実際、複製のソースは孤立した作品ではありません。
before it was
そうなる前に
This may not be the head
これは頭​​ではないかもしれない
This is the earliest header I can trace back so far
これはこれまで遡ることができる最も古いヘッダーです
Two works called Big Money and Little Money
「ビッグマネー」と「リトルマネー」という2つの作品
Together they are called making money
それらを合わせて「お金を稼ぐ」と呼びます
We don't quite know when exactly it works
正確にいつ機能するのかはよくわかりません
So is the author really a woman?
では、作者は本当に女性なのでしょうか？
I'm not sure yet
まだ分​​からない
but likely
しかしおそらく
Then after this there is a
この後は、
A work called "Jade String Garden"
『翡翠の弦の庭』という作品
I'm pretty sure it's a woman's work.
確かに女性の作品だと思います。
Then in "Jade String Garden", there is also a talk about female companions and men's clothing
続いて「Jade String Garden」では女性コンパニオンや紳士服についてのトークも
Well, when Chen Duansheng wrote "Reborn Circle"
さて、チェン・ドゥアンシェンが「Reborn Circle」を書いたとき
He started by saying
彼はこう言い始めた
I read a book called "Jade String Garden"
「翡翠弦の庭」という本を読みました。
very nice
非常に素晴らしい
But I'm very dissatisfied with his ending
でも彼の結末にはとても不満がある
There's a woman in it that I think is pretty good
中にはとても良いと思う女性がいる
Didn't get a very fair treatment in the ending
結末ではあまり公平な扱いを受けられなかった
I think there's a sense of injustice in this
そこには不公平感があると思う
so i'm writing a new novel
だから私は新しい小説を書いています
To reverse the case of a female character I identify with
私が共感する女性キャラクターのケースを逆にするには
This is his motivation for writing "The Reborn Circle" in the first place.
これが、彼が『Reborn Circle』を執筆したそもそもの動機だ。
Because of this, his novel is called "Reborn Circle"
このため、彼の小説は「Reborn Circle」と呼ばれています
right
右
Because his heroine Meng Lijun
なぜなら、彼のヒロインである孟立軍は、
In fact, she said it was a secondary character in "Jade String Circle"
実際、彼女はそれが「Jade String Circle」のサブキャラクターだったと言った
what is it called
それはなんと呼ばれていますか
afterlife afterlife
死後の世界
I can't remember what it's called in Chinese
中国語で何と言うのか思い出せません
that is
あれは
afterlife
死後の世界
OK good next life
OK、良い次の人生
good
良い
Then he is using such a form
それから彼はそのようなフォームを使用しています
to create his Regeneron
彼のリジェネロンを作成する
Okay, so we can say that Regeneron is
さて、Regeneron は
A sequel to Yu Chuanyuan
余伝源の続編
But he's not a sequel
でも彼は続編ではない
he's a whole new story
彼は全く新しい物語だ
So on the one hand
それで、一方では
He did inherit the elements in Yu Chuanyuan.
彼はYu Chuanyuanの要素を継承しました。
some characters
いくつかの文字
but
しかし
He's not like Yu Chuanyuan
他不像御傳元
on the basic spirit
基本的な精神について
Unlike Midenmoto
不像御傳元
Because of Yu Chuanyuan
ユウ・チュアンユアンのせいで
What about the woman he wrote about in disguise?
彼が変装して書いた女性についてはどうですか？
is a comparison
比較です
Um
えーっと
Well
良い
It's just for plot advancement
あくまでプロットを進めるためのものです
It's just for this man and woman to get together
この男と女が集まるためだけに
He's not really trying to explore women's potential
彼は女性の可能性を探ろうとしているわけではない
or possibility
あるいは可能性
This Meng Lijun written by Chen Duansheng
この孟立軍は陳端生によって書かれました
He wholeheartedly wants to be here
彼は心からここにいたいと思っています
The image of Meng Lijun he created has made a big fuss
彼が作成した孟立軍のイメージが大騒ぎになった
He wants to explore through Meng Lijun
彼は孟立軍を通して探検したいと考えています
The various possibilities of this woman's life
この女性の人生のさまざまな可能性
then we must also say
それなら私たちもこう言わなければなりません
In this earlier novel
この初期の小説では
If the hero and heroine can get married and have a happy reunion
主人公とヒロインが結婚して幸せな再会ができたら
that's perfect
それは最高です
don't say anything else
他には何も言わないでください
that's a perfect ending
それは完璧な終わりだ
But for Chen Duansheng
しかし、チェン・ドゥアンシェンにとっては
that's not the end
それは終わりではない
So we see that there are
したがって、次のものがあることがわかります。
very very long episode
とてもとても長いエピソード
It's describing Meng Lijun's repulsion
孟立軍の反発を描いている
push the final destination
最終目的地を押し上げる
he keeps
彼は続ける
If Meng Lijun admits that marriage is his final destination
孟立軍が結婚が最終目的地だと認めたら
In fact, he is constantly working hard to delay the arrival of this end point.
実際、彼はこの終点の到着を遅らせるために絶えず努力しています。
This is the most important part of the regeneration councilor
これが再生評議員の最も重要な部分です
At the same time we must also note
同時に注意しなければならないのは、
in this novel
この小説の中で
his maiden
彼の乙女
Instruct Huangfu Shaohua, we just said that he is a student of Meng Lijun
黄福少華を教えてください。彼は孟立軍の生徒であると先ほど言いました。
Therefore, we must put on a very aggressive attitude in front of Meng Lijun
したがって、孟立軍の前では非常に攻撃的な態度をとらなければなりません
but no matter
でも関係ない
In the novel, Huangfu Shaohua is a man who refuses to marry because of Meng Lijun
小説では、黄福少華は孟立軍のせいで結婚を拒否する男です。
Don't we sound moved?
感動しているように聞こえませんか？
If it was a female reader at the time, she would say
当時の女性読者だったらこう言うだろう
I'm so touched. There is absolutely no such man in this world.
とても感動しました、こんな男はこの世には絶対にいません。
should think so
そう思うべきだ
But if we look at it with the eyes of modern people
でも現代人の目で見たら
Huangfu Shaohua in this novel has been in his first service for three years
この小説の黄福少華は、最初の奉仕に就いて3年になります。
It is not confirmed that Meng Lijun is dead, he refuses to get married
孟立軍氏の死亡は確認されていないが、結婚を拒否している
Is it just for mood?
それはただ気分のためですか？
just for love
ただ愛のために
maybe more than that
もしかしたらそれ以上かもしれない
especially when he saw that his teacher
特に彼が先生のことを見たとき
That is, the prime minister
つまり首相は、
Possibly his fiancée
おそらく彼の婚約者
And when he was trying to bring Meng Lijun back to his family
そして孟立軍を家族の元に帰そうとしたとき
In fact, his real pursuit is not just love.
実際、彼の本当の追求は愛だけではありません。
It is the restoration of a restored family
それは回復された家族の回復です
right
右
It is a recovery system
回復系です
Consolidation again
再び統合
masculinity again
再び男らしさ
Don't blame me for being so negative about rehab
リハビリに否定的な私を責めないでください
The character Huang Fu Shaohua
黄福少華というキャラクター
well then
じゃあ
OK, so we see this cross-dressing design
OK、この女装デザインがわかります
In this garden of regeneration and her previous works
この再生の園とこれまでの作品
has undergone some changes
いくつかの変更が加えられました
And in the later works of this series
そしてこのシリーズのその後の作品では
She's still going to have a lot of renditions
彼女はまだたくさんの演奏をするつもりです
But her effect will be different
しかし、彼女の効果は異なります
I'm very rough here
ここではとても荒れています
Some of the works I have experienced are divided into two series
私が体験した一部の作品は2つのシリーズに分かれています
The series on the left is
左のシリーズは、
It can be said to be the sequel to Garden of Regeneration
『再生の園』の続編とも言える作品
That is to say
つまり
The female authors of the series on the left
左のシリーズの女性作家
They all publicly said that I watched Garden of Regeneration
彼らは皆、私が再生の園を見たと公言しました。
i am moved or i am dissatisfied
感動したり不満を感じたり
That's why I wrote a new work
それで新作を書きました
to respond to him
彼に返事をするために
So the works on the left are all directly responding to the regeneration source
つまり、左側の作品はすべて再生ソースに直接応答しています。
And the series on the right
そして右のシリーズ
They appeared a little later
彼らは少し遅れて現れました
Probably until the middle or late 19th century
おそらく19世紀半ばか後半まで
they didn't say directly
彼らは直接言いませんでした
I'm because I watched the regeneration source
私は再生ソースを見たからです
That's why I came to write my novel
だからこそ私は小説を書きに来たのです
But the traces of the middle influence
しかし、中間の影響の痕跡
It's actually very obvious
それは実際には非常に明白です
if we look at it in the future
後から考えると何が見えるか
Then through the investigation of these two series of works
そして、この二つのシリーズ作品の考察を通じて、
If we focus on the issue of cross-dressing,
女装の問題に焦点を当ててみると、
We can really see the different times
本当にさまざまな時代が見えてきます
and female authors who think differently
と異なる考え方を持つ女性作家
for the same problem
同じ問題に対して
What different ideas would they come up with
彼らはどんな異なるアイデアを思いつくでしょうか
or the solution
または解決策
Well, I'm actually in a hurry
そうですね、実は急いでいるのです
I try to be as fast as possible
できるだけ早くするように努めます
Let's take a look at the one on the left
左側を見てみましょう
first part of the series
シリーズの最初の部分
This one is about a female writer called "Liang Deshen"
これは「梁徳深」という女性作家についての作品です。
Didn't we just say this
私たちはこれを言ったばかりではありませんか
"Chen Duansheng" has not finished writing "Rebirth"
「Chen Duansheng」は「Rebirth」を書き終えていません
just passed away?
亡くなったばかりですか？
Then everyone feels a pity
そうしたらみんな可哀想になるよ
Because at that time, "Rebirth" was a
なぜなら、当時の「Rebirth」は
Works that are very popular with readers
読者からの人気が高い作品
no ending
終わりがない
This is like the drama you watched
これはあなたが見たドラマに似ています
It turned out that the last episode was locked.
最終話はロックされていることが判明しました。
This feeling
この気持
Okay, so everyone feels so sorry.
そうですね、みんなとても残念に思っています。
So there was a Ms. Liang Deshen
そこで梁徳深さんがいました。
She was actually a
彼女は実は、
An older one of the female literary world
女流文壇の先輩。
leader
リーダー
Then because she is older
まあ、彼女は年上だから
So her attitude is of course relatively peaceful.
したがって、彼女の態度は当然比較的穏やかです。
She will not be like "Chen Duansheng"
彼女は「チェン・ドゥアンシェン」のようにはならないだろう
after all the suffering of life
人生のあらゆる苦しみの後に
There is a sense of grief and indignation
悲しみと憤りの気持ちがある
So what Liang Deshen has to do
それで梁徳深は何をしなければならないのか
is to flush this out
これを洗い流すことです
Works full of women's grievances
女性の不満が詰まった作品
give her a softer ending
彼女にもっと穏やかな結末を与えてください
so in general
だから一般的に
modern reader
現代の読者
readers not necessarily
読者は必ずしもそうではない
modern critics are very dissatisfied
現代の批評家は非常に不満を抱いている
The last ending written by Liang Deshen
梁徳深が書いた最後の結末
they all feel
彼らは皆感じている
Doesn't this put this regenerated MP
これは再生したMPを入れるんじゃないの？
Is this story written too often?
この話はあまりにも頻繁に書かれすぎていませんか？
So if we look at it from a modern perspective
では、現代的な視点から見てみると、
indeed
それはそう
But Liang Deshen, with one
しかし、梁徳神は1つで
Compare older women to women to write the story
年上の女性と女性を比較して物語を書く
He's not without what he's read
彼は読んだものがないわけではない
For example, we just saw the show and knew
たとえば、私たちはその番組を見て知ったのですが、
This proverb is very suitable for describing delicate feelings
このことわざは繊細な感情を表現するのに非常に適しています
and inner reading
そして内なる読書
Then actually read the truth
それから実際に真実を読んでください
It is relatively rare in traditional Chinese novels
中国の伝統的な小説では比較的まれです
Except Hong Luomeng
ホン・ルオメンを除く
we rarely see
私たちはめったに見ません
A large section of inner psychological changes
内面の心理的変化の大部分
but Tan Ci novels
しかしタン・チーの小説
Because of the psychology of this Tanci performance
このタンチのパフォーマンスの心理のせいで
gave the writer this convenience
作者にこの便宜を与えた
Let's say we see here
ここを見たとしましょう
In this passage he wrote
彼が書いたこの段落は、
Meng Lijun and his fiancé Huangfu Shaohua
孟立軍と婚約者の黄福少華
What about after the team member?
チームメンバーのその後はどうですか？
know this classic novel
この古典的な小説を知っています
In fact, that has all kinds of things
実際、それはあらゆる種類のものを持っています
So there is another
それで、もう一つあります
a little lady
小さな女性
This little lady was already in
この小さな女性はすでに入っていました
Huangfu Shaohua is here
黄福少華はここにいます
But Huangfu Shaohua refused to marry him
しかし、黄福少華は彼との結婚を拒否した。
Said that I must find Meng Lijun
孟立軍を見つけなければならないと言いました
So he was already fed up, right?
ということは、彼はもう飽きてたんですよね？
Seeing this Huangfu Shaohua and Meng Lijun
この黄風少華と孟立軍を見て
get married
結婚する
He was alone on the wedding night
結婚式の夜、彼は一人だった
Sitting alone in his home
彼の家に一人で座っている
what does he think
彼はどう思いますか
he faces
彼は直面している
to the candlelight
ろうそくの明かりに
silent
静けさ
Must be a woman of the world
きっと世の女性なんだろうな
So I can't make noise, right?
だから騒いではいけないんですよね？
I can't go to barbarian
バーバリアンには行けない
But I'm really worried
でも本当に心配です
This Meng Lijun used to be prime minister
この孟立軍はかつて首相だった
and he is so fierce
そして彼はとても激しいです
what would he do to me like that
彼は私にそんなことをするだろうか
And what about this Huangfu Shaohua?
では、この黄府少華はどうでしょうか？
I used to be so good to him but he refused to marry me
私は彼にとても親切でしたが、彼は私との結婚を拒否しました
Is he affectionate or heartless?
彼は愛情深いのでしょうか、それとも無情なのでしょうか？
If this Meng Lijun is an idle person, I'll forget it
この孟立軍が怠け者なら忘れるよ
What the hell would I do if he wasn't a slob
彼がだらしない人じゃなかったら一体どうするだろう
I'm helpless
私は無力です
Because his father is a treacherous minister, he has been arrested by this
彼の父親は裏切り者なので、この事件で逮捕された
has been wrecked
破壊されました
ok then we can see
わかりました、それではわかります
Through this Ms. Liu's inner monologue
劉さんの内なる独白を通して
In fact, Liang Desheng showed us
実際、梁徳勝さんが見せてくれました。
a traditional polygamy
一個傳統多妻
polygamous family
一夫多妻制の家族
A woman in a family with wives and concubines
妻や側室がいる家庭の女性
A complexity in his heart
彼の心の中にある複雑な思い
He is not like the kind of wives and concubines written in this series
彼はこのシリーズに書かれているような妻や妾とは違います。
What are you going to do with poison?
毒を使ってどうするつもりですか？
Or throw some other party's child to death?
それとも相手の子供を投げ殺しますか？
take the dog to bite him
犬を連れて行って噛ませてください
no he didn't write like this
いいえ、彼はこのように書いていません
He will tell you how ungrateful and fierce this heart is.
この心がいかに無慈悲であるかを彼は教えてくれるでしょう。
This is enough
これで十分です
good
良い
This is a detailed description of female psychology by a female writer
女性心理を女性ライターが詳しく解説します
look at the next example
次の例を見てください
This is another female writer named Hou Zhi
こちらも侯志という女性作家です。
She is also a woman who has the position of leader in the female literary circle
彼女は女流文壇のリーダー的な立場にある女性でもある。
Her husband is soft round student
彼女の夫は柔らかい丸い学生です
This Hou Zhi is very, very interesting
この侯志はとてもとても面白いです
she's a super complicated woman
彼女はとても複雑な女性です
On the one hand, she has to put on a
一方で、彼女は服を着なければなりません
She is a female teacher gesture
彼女は女性教師のジェスチャーです
So she wants to teach women to obey the rules
そこで彼女は女性たちにルールを守るよう教えたいと考えている
You know what? If you don't follow the rules
ルールを守らないと
there will be riots
暴動が起こるだろう
but on the other hand
しかし一方で
she's done some really weird things herself
彼女は自分自身でいくつかの本当に奇妙なことをしました
For example, she obviously belongs to a famous family
たとえば、彼女は明らかに有名な家族に属しています。
But she was able to contact the publisher
しかし、彼女は出版社に連絡することができました
Help Her Publish Commercial Publishing
商業出版の出版を手伝ってください
help her publish her novel
彼女の小説の出版を手伝ってください
Did you know that Chen Dunshen did such a thing?
チェン・ドゥンシェンがそのようなことをしたことをご存知ですか？
absolutely not
絶対違う
so we can see
それで私たちは見ることができます
A traditional woman, he has many complex layers
伝統的な女性、彼は多くの複雑な層を持っています
We really can't learn from what he said
私たちは彼の言ったことから本当に学ぶことができません
or what he wrote to judge him
あるいは彼を裁くために彼が書いたもの
You have to put him together on all levels
あらゆるレベルで彼をまとめなければなりません
He will be a three-dimensional person
三次元の人になるよ
Well, this Hou Zhi has actually rewritten Fate of Rebirth
さて、この侯志は実は再生の運命を書き換えたものです。
What about after he rewrote it?
彼がそれを書き直した後はどうですか？
he rewrites , so he has to read , right
彼は書き直すので、彼は読まなければなりません、そうです
What about women, they are the best readers for women
女性はどうでしょうか。女性は女性にとって最高の読者です
As for Hou Zhi, he read it completely
侯志に関しては、彼はそれを完全に読みました
The Charm of Chen Duansheng's Fate of Rebirth
チェン・ドゥアンシェンの運命の再生の魅力
But he also read about his danger
しかし、彼は自分の危険についても読んだ
Because after seeing the fate of rebirth, it will be in the hearts of women
生まれ変わる運命を見た後、それは女性の心に残るから
planted a seed of uneasiness
不安の種を植え付けた
Then as a life coach
その後、ライフコーチとして
Hou Zhi like this, he thinks he can't do things like this
侯志はこうだ、自分にはこんなことはできないと思っている
So, he wrote another novel
そこで彼は別の小説を書きました
The novel is called Reinvention
その小説は「再発明」と呼ばれています
That is to say
つまり
Simply put, the story of Rebirth
簡単に言えば、再生の物語
with his subsequent role
彼のその後の役割について
It's like breaking the sky
まるで空を割るようだ
Break the harmony of the world, yin and yang, men and women
世界の調和を崩す、陰と陽、男と女
I have to make it up again
もう一度仲直りしなければならない
So he wrote this book called "The Novel of Reinventing the Sky"
そこで彼は「空を作り直す小説」という本を書きました。
It says
それは言う
This Meng Lijun married Huangfu Shaohua and gave birth to a daughter
この孟立軍は黄福少華と結婚し、娘を出産しました。
Just as smart and beautiful as him
彼と同じくらい賢くて美しい
only
それだけ
Because I was spoiled by Mr. Meng Li
孟李さんに甘えたので。
So her temper and her ambition are more out of the ordinary than Meng Lijun
したがって、彼女の気性と野心は孟立軍よりも常軌を逸しています。
This daughter said since she was a child
この娘は子供の頃からこう言っていました。
i want to be a dancer day
ダンサーになりたい日
if
もしも
when we are now affected by zero sequels
続編ゼロの影響を受けているとき
So if your daughter says she wants to be a dancer
それで、あなたの娘がダンサーになりたいと言ったら
you may be happy
あなたは幸せかもしれません
but
しかし
I know
知っている
To be a dancer in this novel
この小説の中でダンサーになること
this is a very serious matter
これは非常に深刻な問題です
really
本当
This daughter will really become a queen
この娘は本当に女王になるだろう
After becoming queen
女王になってから
She is really heading towards becoming a dancer step by step
彼女は本当にダンサーとして一歩ずつ進んでいます
go to this goal
この目標に向かって行きます
Of course, this country is in turmoil and the world is in chaos.
もちろん、この国は混乱にあり、世界は混乱に陥っています。
In the end, the warehouse that caused this piece of land needs to be cleaned up.
結局のところ、この土地の原因となった倉庫は片付ける必要があります。
what about this time
今回はどうですか
This mother, Meng Lijun, appeared
この母親、孟立軍が登場
Because the focus is not on Meng Lijun's daughter
孟立軍の娘に焦点が当てられていないため
What kind of earth-shaking things did you do?
どのような地球を揺るがすようなことをしましたか？
The focus is on the character Meng Lijun
孟立軍というキャラクターに焦点を当てる
how to reflect on your past
自分の過去をどのように振り返るか
Let's see, this is another inner monologue
ほら、これもまた内なる独り言だ
what about here
ここはどうですか
This Meng Lijun
この孟立軍
His daughter has been in this terrible disaster
彼の娘はこのひどい災害に遭った
Meng Lijun says
孟立軍 言う
Back then, I just wanted to be an official
あの頃はただ公務員になりたかったんです
my mother is sick
私の母は病気です
dying
死んでいる
I couldn't bear to see her
彼女を見るのが耐えられなかった
my husband fiance
私の夫の婚約者
because miss me miss me lovesickness
私がいなくて寂しいから
dying too
死ぬのも
I am not only not moved
感動しないだけじゃない
He hates me and I think he loves the world
彼は私を憎んでいます、そして私は彼が世界を愛していると思います
Then I just think about my husband insisting on me being with him
それから私は夫が私と一緒にいることを主張していることだけを考えます
where is my fiancé
私の婚約者はどこですか
my student my student insisted that i marry him
私の生徒 私の生徒が私に彼と結婚するよう主張しました
is a disgraceful thing
それは恥ずべきことだ
I'm a teacher, how can I marry my student?
私は教師ですが、どうすれば生徒と結婚できますか?
Then I completely ruined this family of mine.
それから私はこの家族を完全に破滅させました。
he he is my daughter
彼は私の娘です
My daughter wants to learn from Wu Zetian to steal the country
娘は武則天から国を盗むことを学びたいと考えています
what about me
私はどうなの
Back then, I was just practicing for the position of prime minister.
当時、私はちょうど首相の座を目指して練習していました。
I'm right, uh, to the emperor, to my father, to my husband
私は正しい、ええと、皇帝に対して、父に対して、夫に対して
so disrespectful
とても失礼な
think about it now
今考えてみてください
Everything that's happening now is retribution
今起こっていることはすべて報復だ
It's all because of my bad behavior in the past
全ては私の過去の悪行のせいです
So I'm suffering now, uh, totally deserved
だから私は今苦しんでいる、ああ、それは当然のことだ
Wasn't what I did before just like Qingshou?
私が前にやったことはまるで青寿のようではありませんか？
No wonder what my daughter is doing now is more vicious than tigers and wolves
娘が今やっていることは虎や狼よりも凶悪であるのも不思議ではありません
good
良い
Although I am talented
才能があるのに
I though
でも、
Conspiracy
陰謀
Although I never thought of harming anyone before
今まで人を傷つけようと思ったことは一度もなかったのに
but
しかし
as a female
女性として
What I absolutely shouldn't be is that I'm greedy to blend in
絶対にいけないのは、溶け込もうとする貪欲さだ
I shouldn't just think about being an officer
役員になることだけを考えるべきではない
have to wait
待たなければならない
Then I won't talk about it
じゃあそれについては話さないよ
I mean, my daughter is like this now.
というか、今の娘がこんな感じです。
I must strictly discipline my granddaughter
孫娘を厳しく躾けなければなりません
must make her a
彼女を
Well-Being Women
健康な女性
Well, this is Hou Zhijie
さて、こちらは侯志傑です
Meng Lijun's
孟立軍さん
Meng Lijun reflects on his own words
孟立軍が自身の言葉を振り返る
to deliver a message to his readers
読者にメッセージを届けるために
right
右
no matter how talented you are
どんなに才能があっても
but you can't
でもそれはできません
Obsessed with some so-called civic principles
いわゆる市民原則に執着している
Of course here we have to say
もちろんここで言わなければなりません
Wait a minute
ちょっと待って
This Ms. Hou, you completely misunderstood our Chen Duansheng
この侯さん、あなたは私たちの陳端生を完全に誤解しています。
Meng Lijun written by Chen Duansheng
孟立軍、陳端生著
Is he just greedy to fit in?
彼はただ周りに合わせたいと欲深いだけなのでしょうか？
no
いいえ
He is pursuing a life pursuit
彼は人生の追求を追求している
why don't you see that side
なぜその側面を見ないのですか
because of this
このため
So contemporary readers and critics
したがって、現代の読者や批評家は
Regarding what Hou Zhi wrote in
侯志が書いたことについて
In Zhaotian, of course, I don't particularly like it.
もちろん趙天では特に好きではありません。
but even so
しかしそれでも
i still have to say
まだ言わなければなりません
if we revisit this
これをもう一度振り返ってみると
"Hou Zhi" wrote that when the sky was shining
『侯志』は空が輝いていたときこう書いた。
we can see
見える
When Hou Zhi imagines someone who wants to do
Hou Zhi がやりたい人を想像するとき
The time of women in "Five Folds"
「ファイブフォールズ」における女性の時間
His writing actually reveals unconsciously
彼の文章は実は無意識に明らかにしている
a mood
気分
a pleasure
喜び
So as for the last
それで最後に関しては
Meng Lijun's self-reflection
孟立軍の反省
cannot dissolve the middle of this novel
この小説の真ん中を溶かすことはできません
all those for this woman
それらすべてはこの女性のために
I want to do "50% off the sky"
「空の50％オフ」をやりたいです。
the will to rule the world
世界を支配する意志
not digested
消化されていない
Then this is Zai Zhaotian from "Hou Zhi"
それから、こちらは「侯志」のザイ・ジャオティアンです。
We can see that it is a negative response
否定的な反応であることがわかります
then look at this
それからこれを見てください
This is about the nineteenth century
これは19世紀のことです
A woman in the late
晩年の女性
She also watched "Rebirth"
『リバース』も観た
was very moved
とても感動しました
she likes it
彼女はそれが好き
But he also has a point
しかし、彼にも一理ある
His opinion is not about the Meng Lijun created by Chen Duansheng.
彼の意見は陳端生が創作した孟立軍に関するものではない。
This wants to be an official so much
これはすごく公務員になりたい
his opinion is not here
彼の意見はここにはありません
This, Qiu Xinru's opinion is
これは邱新如の意見です。
This Meng Lijun is too unfilial
この孟立軍は親不孝すぎる
Because Meng Lijun refused to restore women's clothing
孟立軍が婦人服の復元を拒否したため
So his parents were very, very worried
それで彼の両親はとてもとても心配していました
And still seriously ill
そして今も重病です
Well, Qiu Xinru thinks that everything else is easy to say
まあ、Qiu Xinru は、他のことはすべて言うのは簡単だと考えています
People can't let their parents worry so much
人は親にそんなに心配させられない
So at this point, he can't accept it at all.
したがって、現時点では彼はそれをまったく受け入れることができません。
So he thinks, this dream of Meng Lijun's life
そこで彼は、孟立軍の人生の夢は何だろうと考えました。
he appreciates it very much
彼はそれをとても高く評価しています
But he thinks Meng Lijun is an imperfect character
しかし、彼は孟立軍が不完全な人物であると考えています
So he wanted to create a character
それで彼はキャラクターを作りたかったのです
It has the material of Meng Lijun
孟立軍の素材があります
Can reach the same height as Meng Lijun's industrial
孟立軍の産業と同じ高さに達することができます
at the same time
同時に
is a perfect person
完璧な人です
So guys, do you think this is possible?
それで皆さん、これは可能だと思いますか？
Everyone is so optimistic
みんなすごく楽観的だね
Y'all, I thought everyone was going to say no way right away.
みんな、すぐにみんながダメだと言うだろうと思ってた。
It's really hard
本当に大変です
So
それで
This Qiu Xinru is here
この邱新如はここにいます
Bishenghua Bishenghua means this book is very good, right?
Bishenghua Bishenghua はこの本がとても良いという意味ですよね?
Myohi Ikebana
妙比生花
he is here
彼はここにいます
What about a character created in Bishenghua's novel?
美聖華の小説で創作されたキャラクターについてはどうですか？
In all respects
あらゆる点で
Whether it's character settings
キャラ設定とか
As far as his life experiences are concerned
彼の人生経験に関する限り、
In fact, they are all very, very similar to Meng Lijun
実際、彼らは皆、孟立軍に非常によく似ています。
The only difference is
唯一の違いは、
What about the character he created?
彼が作ったキャラクターはどうですか？
He will not be like Meng Lijun
彼は孟立軍のようにはならないだろう
use so firmly
しっかりと使ってください
And violently collide with the system
そしてシステムと激しく衝突する
what about his female character
彼の女性キャラクターはどうですか
is taking a
を取っています
On the one hand, work hard to make contributions
一方で、成果を上げるために一生懸命働く
On the other hand
一方で
What about your words and deeds?
あなたの言動はどうですか？
Trying to
努力値
an image that tries to constrain
束縛しようとするイメージ
Let's take a look at a short
短いものを見てみましょう
This is his heroine
これが彼のヒロインです
It's the same thing again, heartbroken
また同じことだ、心が痛む
He said that this is also the pressure he faced to restore women's clothing
これは婦人服を復活させるために直面​​したプレッシャーでもあると彼は語った。
His parents and so on told him that
彼の両親などが彼にこう言いました。
you can't go on like this
このままではいけない
Mom and Dad are in jail, need to hold grandchildren, etc.
お父さんとお母さんは刑務所にいて、孫を抱く必要があるなど。
he's under a lot of pressure
彼は大きなプレッシャーにさらされている
So he said it doesn't work
それで彼はそれはうまくいかないと言った
had to forget
忘れなければならなかった
I have to make a copy
コピーを作らなければなりません
I have to go back to being a woman
女性に戻らなければなりません
Looks like I have to get married, right?
どうやら結婚しなければならないようですね？
blow off cross seam
クロスシームを吹き飛ばす
This was supposed to be a perfect marriage
完璧な結婚生活になるはずだった
A symbol of a happy marriage
幸せな結婚の象徴
If you congratulate someone on their marriage today
今日、誰かの結婚を祝福するとしたら
It should be good that you write blow off the cross seam
クロスシームの吹き飛ばしを書くと良いでしょう
but
しかし
But he said blow off the cross seam thing
でも彼はクロスシームを吹き飛ばせって言った
makes me very depressed
私をとても落ち込ませます
Next he said
次に彼は言いました
If women in this world get married
この世の女性が結婚したら
there are so many unfree places
不自由な場所がたくさんある
This is of course compared to his time in the past
もちろんこれは過去の彼の時代と比較したものです
It's this male freedom I've ever enjoyed
それは私がこれまで享受してきた男性の自由です
He said that even if someone exposed
たとえ誰かが暴露したとしても、と彼は言った。
i am female
私は女性です
Even if things leak
物が漏れても
Then I have to take off my male officer
それなら男性役員を脱がなければなりません
And the records of women in the book
そしてこの本に登場する女性たちの記録
Even so
たとえそうであっても
I'm fine, I don't want to get married
大丈夫、結婚したくない
as long as you don't get married
結婚しない限り
because as long as you don't get married
結婚しない限りは
I won't have those detentions.
そんな拘留は受けないよ
Although my heart is so
私の心はそうだけど
But my mom and dad won't let me do that
でもお父さんもお母さんもそんなことはさせてくれない
They don't think it's a good life
彼らはそれが良い人生だとは思っていない
So when my parents ask me
それで両親が私に尋ねると、
I can't help it, I have to listen to them
仕方ない、聞くしかない
Because if I don't listen to my parents
親の言うことを聞かなかったら
that would be so disrespectful
それはとても失礼なことだろう
so so i thought
それで私はそう思いました
I know my ambition in this life
私はこの人生における自分の野心を知っています
I'm afraid there is no way to really achieve it.
残念ながらそれを本当に達成する方法はありません。
so we can see
それで私たちは見ることができます
this
これ
The woman in Bishenghua
美聖花の女性
The biggest difference between her and Meng Qianjun is that
彼女と孟乾軍の最大の違いは、
She will pass through one of her own
彼女は自分自身のものを通過するでしょう
What happens after the rational one becomes difficult?
合理的なものが難しくなった後はどうなるでしょうか？
she will take orders from women
彼女は女性からの注文を受けます
She will put her dissatisfaction, wish
彼女は不満や願いをぶつけるだろう
Feelings of injustice are buried
不公平感は埋もれてしまう
And with a mask
そしてマスク付きで
put on a mask and come out
マスクをして出て行け
to face her future life
彼女のこれからの人生と向き合うために
This is mentioned in Bishenghua
これは美書華に記載されています
Another option
別のオプション
Of course this solution for us
もちろん、このソリューションは私たちにとっても
seems to be less than perfect
完璧ではないようです
In Bishenghua, in fact
実は美聖花では
She also kept describing the heroine over and over again.
彼女はまた、ヒロインについて何度も何度も説明し続けました。
she went to the end
彼女は最後まで行きました
Until the end of this novel
この小説が終わるまで
She is a last resort
彼女は最後の手段だ
such a mood to face
直面するような気分
Let's look at a very extreme example
非常に極端な例を見てみましょう
This is a really nice example
これは本当に良い例です
We just said that there are many female
女性が多いと先ほど言いましたが、
are constantly responding in various ways.
常にさまざまな方法で対応しています。
Some of the proposed
提案されたものの一部
The Dilemma of Women's Lives
女性の人生のジレンマ
Then it is true that the later the nineteenth century
そうすると、確かに19世紀後半には
There will be more and more strange answers
どんどんおかしな答えが出てくるよ
really weird answer
本当に奇妙な答え
They will experiment with different ways of unraveling
彼らは解明するさまざまな方法を実験します
then imagine
それから想像してください
The consequences of various ways of unwinding
さまざまなリラックス方法の結果
So let's look at this example
それではこの例を見てみましょう
This work is called "Flower Dream"
この作品は「フラワードリーム」といいます。
it has many special places
特別な場所がたくさんあります
first it's not this
まずこれじゃないよ
Created by the women of Jiang Zhe's generation
江沢氏の世代の女性たちが作った
The author is Li Guiyu
著者は李桂宇です。
He actually grew up in Shaanxi when he was a child
彼は実際に子供の頃陝西省で育ちました
Then when he grows up
それから彼が成長したとき
He went all the way from the west to the far south and got married in Fujian
彼は西の果てから南の果てまではるばる行き、福建省で結婚した
So he himself is saying that he has passed
それで本人も合格したって言ってた
a long time
長い間
In the end it settled in Fujian
結局福建省に落ち着いた
Liu Huameng was created when he was in Fujian
劉華蒙は福建省にいたときに作られました。
How many pieces of Liu Huameng are there? How many times?
劉華蒙の作品は何枚ありますか?何回ありますか?
There are 360 ​​times
360回あります
How many words? About 5 million words
単語数は? 約 500 万語
This may be the longest Chinese novel we now know
これは私たちが現在知っている中で最も長い中国の小説かもしれません
Do you think there is such a book
そんな本があると思いますか
And our books none of our textbooks tell us
そして私たちの本には教科書には何も書かれていません
is that right
そうですか
Such a creation of 5 million words
500万語のこのような創造物
not an obscure work
曖昧な作品ではない
In fact, according to records in the Fujian area
実際、福建省地域の記録によると、
it's a very very famous
それはとてもとても有名です
and popular works
そして人気作品も
how popular is it
どれくらい人気ですか
same it has no way to publish
同じく公開する方法がない
Because it is too much, it cannot be engraved
多すぎるので彫れません
think about it
考えてみてください
Gou Taiming may be needed to sponsor
Gou Taiming がスポンサーとして必要になる可能性がある
In that era, Guo Taiming came to sponsor
その時代に郭台銘がスポンサーになった
it's going to cost too much
費用がかかりすぎるだろう
So no matter what to do, use super
だから何をするにしても、スーパーを使用してください
Spread in the form of Gaoben
Gaobenの形で広がる
How popular can it be?
どこまで人気が出るでしょうか？
In fact, there were bookstores in ancient times.
実は古代にも本屋がありました。
Rent a bookshop in the nineteenth century
19世紀に本屋を借りよう
"Flower Dream" is one
「フラワードリーム」もそのひとつ
at least hateful works
少なくとも嫌な作品
That is, everyone wants to rush
つまり、誰もが急ぎたいのです
works to rent
レンタルする作品
besides
そのほか
Another effect is
もう一つの効果は、
it can be turned into a property
財産に変えることができる
what kind of property
どのような物件ですか
it is
それはです
part of dowry
持参金の一部
That is to say
つまり
when a girl was young
女の子が小さかった頃
she copied it herself
彼女はそれを自分でコピーした
or at home
または家で
Sisters and mothers help to copy
姉妹や母親が写経を手伝ってくれる
let her get married
彼女に結婚させてください
You can bring "Liuhuameng"
「柳華孟」をお持ちいただけます
extra
追加
become her own
彼女のものになる
part of the property
財産の一部
and may be transmissible
そして伝染する可能性がある
We record from such
そんな中から録音していきます
you can see
見ることができます
This is a
これは
how to get attention
注目を集める方法
and favorite works
そして好きな作品
Interestingly
興味深いことに
In fact, the author did not
実際、作者はそうではなかった
finish this work
この仕事を終わらせる
He probably wrote up to 357.
おそらく357まで書いたと思われます。
He wrote three hundred fifty-seven
彼は 357 冊を書きました
die before writing
書く前に死ぬ
later in the twentieth century
20世紀後半
Only two modern female writers helped her finish writing
彼女が執筆を終えるのを助けたのはたった二人の現代女性作家だけだった
But because it was written to 357, the overall situation is actually determined
でも357に書いてあるから全体の状況は実は決まってる
So she is not the same as Regeneron
つまり、彼女はリジェネロンと同じではありません
Chen Duansheng of Zaiyuan wrote a key point and stopped
ZaiyuanのChen Duanshengさんが要点を書いて止めた
And Liu Huameng didn't stop until the end.
そして劉華蒙は最後まで止まらなかった。
In fact, the latter can be completed with a little bit of hard work.
実際、後者は少しの労力で完了できます。
The big picture of the novel has not been changed
小説の全体像は変わっていない
This novel has 5 million words
この小説には 500 万語あります
Of course I can't tell you what she's talking about.
もちろん、彼女が何について話しているのかはわかりません。
too complicated
複雑すぎる
She is involved in the stories of at least three generations of several big families
彼女は、いくつかの大家族の少なくとも 3 世代の物語に関わっています。
So it should be called Family Saga
だからそれはファミリーサーガと呼ばれるべきです
This is the Yamato novel
これはヤマトの小説です
There is no way to effectively introduce to you
効果的に紹介する方法がない
I just point out that in this
ただこの中で指摘しておきますが、
There are also stories about women disguised as men
女性が男装した話もある
and more than one
そして複数の
It can be said that it is a string of star conferences
スター会議の連続と言える
That's almost all the female characters in it
登場するのはほぼ女性キャラばかり
She's been through one in her life
彼女は人生で一つのことを経験している
stage of masculinity
男らしさの段階
And what?
そして何？
through cross-dressing
女装を通して
achieve a certain success
一定の成功を収める
what about inside
中はどうですか
there is a first heroine
最初のヒロインがいる
called
呼ばれた
girl
女の子
when she is a female name
彼女が女性の名前の場合
Her name is Guibifang
彼女の名前はギビファンです
when she was male
彼女が男性だったとき
Her name is Gui Hengkui
彼女の名前はグイ・ヘンクイです
anyway this one
とにかくこれ
this this
これこれ
this expensive
この高価な
ma'am or mr.
奥様またはミスター。
what about her
彼女はどうですか
yes
はい
The author wants to shape a past and present
著者は過去と現在を形作りたいと考えています
An image of the most remarkable woman
最も注目に値する女性のイメージ
so is she the best
それで彼女は最高ですか
Everyone is going to read the novel
みんな小説を読むつもりです
to be able to judge
判断できるようになる
What we want to emphasize here is that
ここで強調したいのは、
what about this woman
この女性はどうですか
She is because she disguised herself as a man
彼女は男装したからだ
Whether it is literary or intellectual
文学的なものであっても、知識的なものであっても、
Martial arts are also good
格闘技もいいですね
She is a master of ancient scriptures
彼女は古代経典の達人です
that's awesome
それはすごいです
How powerful is this emperor?
この皇帝はどのくらいの権力を持っているのでしょうか？
take her
彼女を連れて行きます
The story is set in the Tang Dynasty
物語の舞台は唐の時代
So it's proven
それで証明されたんだよ
what about the emperor
皇帝はどうですか
seal her as
彼女を封印する
should be Guangxi
広西チワン族自治区のはずだ
sorry
ごめん
because it's been a while
久しぶりだから
a bit unsure
少し自信がありません
In short, Yunnan and Guangxi are a big town in the southwest
一言で言えば、雲南省と広西チワン族自治区は南西部の大きな町です
it is a king
それは王様です
to this point
ここまで
so what's interesting
それで何が面白いの
Its identity will still be revealed
その正体は今後も明らかになるだろう
when it is exposed
それが暴露されたとき
It was forced to give up its status as the king
王としての地位を放棄せざるを得なくなった
it's getting married to its fiancé
それは婚約者と結婚することになる
And it has to give up his throne to its husband
そして王位を夫に譲らなければならない
And it becomes a Queen itself
そしてそれは女王そのものになる
a queen
一個皇后
not a queen
女王ではない
Then of course this lady is very reluctant
それからもちろんこの女性は非常に消極的です
Well, there is a very interesting description in the novel that says
さて、小説の中に次のような非常に興味深い記述があります。
How reluctant is he?
彼はどのくらい消極的ですか？
He's not willing until he actually dies
彼は実際に死ぬまでその気はない
What about his true soul?
彼の本当の魂はどうなっているのでしょうか？
just lightly
ほんの軽く
Arrived on a fairy mountain
妖精の山に到着
Of course we know that in the traditional
もちろん、伝統的にはそれがわかっています
Often there is a frame of this discount
よくこの割引の枠があります
That is to say, it would have been
つまり、そうなるはずだった
He is a fairy, because he committed a crime, so he was brought down to the world to walk around
彼は妖精です、彼は罪を犯したので、歩き回るためにこの世界に降ろされました
So is this lady
この女性もそうです
After his journey of conquest of the soul arrived at Xianshan
魂の征服の旅が仙山に到着した後
The owner of the fairy mountain there told him
そこの妖精山の主は彼に言いました。
It's not your time yet, take this pill obediently
まだその時期じゃない、素直にこの薬を飲みなさい
you'll be fine
あなたは大丈夫です
sorry , two pills
ごめんなさい、二錠です
This pill is called... what?
この錠剤の名前は...何ですか?
Qin Dan
チン・ダン
Why is it called Qindan?
なぜ秦丹と呼ばれるのですか？
It means to be in the heart of this noble lady
それはこの高貴な女性の心の中にいることを意味します
Plant a seed that can develop the love between men and women
男女の愛を育む種を蒔こう
Only in this way can he start his marriage with his husband
このようにしてのみ、彼は夫との結婚生活を始めることができます
In other words, the relationship between men and women did not exist for him.
つまり、彼にとって男女の関係は存在しなかったのです。
It is to allow him to continue his life on earth for a period of time
それは彼が一定期間地上での生活を続けられるようにするためです
So there is only one...
ということで、一つだけあるんですが…
a divine power an external force
一個神力 一個外力
planted in his heart
彼の心に植え付けられた
and it's temporary
そしてそれは一時的なものです
OK good
いいよ
I think this imagination is more
この想像力はもっとあると思う
Jueqin Valley
覚琴渓谷
what's more interesting
もっと面白いのは何ですか
then he eats this
それから彼はこれを食べる
What about after this heavy sheet music?
この重い楽譜の後はどうなるでしょうか？
What about him? He was originally because
彼はどうですか? 彼はもともと次のような理由でした。
He vomited blood and died because he was too
彼は吐血して死亡した。
Sad and angry, that's it
悲しくて怒って、それだけです
I am the only one in this Botian industry
このBotian業界には私だけがいます
I saved up for nothing
無駄に貯めた
Give it to someone else and I don't love him at all
他の人にあげても、私は彼をまったく愛していない
Well this he too
まあ、これは彼もです
Sad and angry, so what?
悲しくて怒って、だから何？
He has this blood clot in his chest
彼の胸には血栓がある
What about the condensed air of blood?
血液が凝縮した空気はどうでしょうか？
he passed out because of it
彼はそのせいで気を失った
he ate this
彼はこれを食べました
What about after this heavy sheet music?
この重い楽譜の後はどうなるでしょうか？
His blood clot melts away
彼の血栓は溶けてなくなる
melted temporarily
一時的に溶けた
so he didn't die
だから彼は死ななかった
Just go back to the human world and continue to do his work
人間界に戻って仕事を続けてください
queen
女王
so we can
だから私たちはできる
So even close blood
だから近い血でも
Exhausted, originally filled with grief and indignation
疲れ果て、当初は悲しみと憤りでいっぱいだった
At this time, it's only temporary
現時点ではあくまで一時的なものです
got one
1つもらいました
but only temporarily
しかし一時的にだけ
This novel has another very special
この小説にはもう一つ特別な点があります
It is he who writes about women's desire in a positive way
女性の欲望をポジティブに書いているのは彼です
the heroine
ヒロイン
Although she has no love between men and women
彼女には男女の愛はないが、
Her relationship between men and women is outsider
彼女の男女関係は部外者だ
But she has another feeling
しかし彼女には別の感情がある
and lust
そして欲望
object of this affection
この愛情の対象
not her husband
彼女の夫ではありません
But her boudoir secretly has a woman
しかし彼女の私室には密かに女性がいる
And of course this woman
そしてもちろんこの女性も
We're going to go back to this traditional situation again
私たちは再びこの伝統的な状況に戻るつもりです
This woman is actually her husband's second wife
この女性は実は夫の後妻である
Also her cousin
彼女のいとこも
So her feelings are all pinned on
だから彼女の気持ちはすべて固定されている
on this sister of hers
彼女のこの妹について
So how far-fetched is this feeling?
それでは、この感情はどれほど現実離れしているのでしょうか？
Their feelings are for each other
彼らの気持ちはお互いに向けられている
This cousin and this lady
このいとことこの女性
They used to be female companions in male middle school together
彼らはかつて男子高校の女友達だった
What we see are two
私たちが見ているのは二つです
beautiful great general
美しい偉大な将軍
killing
殺す
fight on other fields
他のフィールドで戦う
Once Miss Bea
かつてミス・ビー
Seriously injured, it looks like it won't work
重傷、もうダメっぽい
same with his cousin
彼のいとこも同じです
Wearing armor is the image of a male general
甲冑を着ているのは男性将軍のイメージです
My uncle described it
私の叔父がそれを説明しました
This cousin heard that your general
このいとこはあなたの将軍のことを聞きました
dying
死んでいる
His heart is like a knife
彼の心はナイフのようだ
he vomits blood immediately
彼はすぐに血を吐きます
And it's like blue blood
そしてそれは青い血のようなものです
call my brother
兄に電話する
Because the two of them are dressed as women and men
二人は女装と男装をしているので、
I can't live anymore
もう生きていけない
Uncle said
おじさんは言いました。
Poor Suspicious Girl
哀れな不審な少女
Xietu Qingpeng has died
シエトゥ・チンペン氏が死去
This cousin was so sad that she died.
このいとこはとても悲しんで亡くなりました。
How loving the children and sisters were
子供たちと姉妹たちはなんて愛情深いんだろう
Entering the ghost gate with you until death
死ぬまで君と一緒に鬼門に入る
we can see this narrative
私たちはこの物語を見ることができます
What kind of intensity should be used to describe the relationship between these two women?
この二人の女性の関係をどのような激しさで表現すべきでしょうか?
What about this feeling?
この気持ちはどうでしょうか？
I said Dream of the Red Chamber
赤い部屋の夢って言った
is still crying
まだ泣いています
What about the feelings in this flower dream?
この花の夢の気持ちはどうですか？
is blood
血です
It will always use bright red blood
常に真っ赤な血を使う
to express the relationship between the two women
二人の女性の関係を表現するために
Concentration and intensity of emotion
感情の集中力と強さ
what about a scene like this
こんなシーンはどうでしょうか
Actually more than once
実は複数回
to the second half of the novel
小説の後半へ
Where is this heroine, this noble lady?
このヒロイン、この高貴な女性はどこにいるのですか？
Because of the love pill she ate
彼女が飲んだ惚れ薬のせいで
I can only save her for a while
彼女を救えるのはしばらくの間だけ
What about after it works?
それが機能した後はどうですか？
She can't stand this vulgar creature
彼女はこの下品な生き物に我慢できない
so she has to leave
だから彼女は去らなければならない
So it means to die
つまり死ぬことを意味する
what about after she died
彼女が死んだ後はどうなるのか
Where's her cousin?
彼女のいとこはどこですか？
no way to accept
受け入れる方法がない
same she again
また同じ彼女
she can't live
彼女は生きていけない
The novel is about this cousin
その小説はこのいとこについてのものです
Kiss yourself with a sword
直接拿劍自吻
under the light wind like the wind
微風の下で風のように
She kisses this and wipes the neck directly
彼女はこれにキスして首を拭きます
when you put him to bed
彼を寝かせるとき
he is almost dead
彼はほとんど死んでいる
The narrator tells us again
ナレーターが再び語る
between the two of them
二人の間で
Wanlu Love
ワンルー・ラブ
Entanglement can never be untied
絡み合いは決して解けない
This and that heavy engine list
あれやこれやの重いエンジンリスト
The weighted seed grows a tiny seedling
重みのある種が小さな苗を育てる
after twenty years
二十年後
It's totally different
全然違うよ
their love is
彼らの愛は
getting tighter
きつくなっている
Then this cousin is using his blood
じゃあこのいとこは自分の血を使ってるのか
to pay back this cousin
このいとこに恩返しするために
give him affection
彼に愛情を与えてください
But he's not dead yet
でも彼はまだ死んでいない
Did not die for the sake of
のために死んだわけではない
describe this feeling
この気持ちを説明する
deep and his
ディープと彼の
the will to repay his feelings with death
その思いを死をもって報いるという意志
firm
固い
So soon after
それですぐに
where is this cousin
このいとこはどこですか
she deliberately
彼女は故意に
a large banquet venue
大きな宴会場
It's when the whole family gathers
家族全員が集まるときです
He ascended he ascended one of the houses
彼は登った 彼は家の一つに登った
tall building
高い建物
opened the people around him, and then he committed suicide by jumping off the building
周囲の人たちに暴言を吐いた後、ビルから飛び降り自殺した
this time it worked
今回はうまくいきました
In the novel, he committed suicide by jumping off a building
小説では彼はビルから飛び降り自殺した
He sprinkled blood on the face
彼は顔に血を振りかけた
Achievement party name is only for love
達成パーティー名は愛だけ
In this "Liu Hua Meng"
この「劉華蒙」では
We can see what he describes
彼が説明している内容がわかります
i want to be in
入りたいです
I believe I haven't seen it in any other Chinese classical novels
他の中国の古典小説では見たことがないと思います
I think if in our time
私たちの時代だったらと思います
Now let's talk about gay literature or same-sex relationships
さあ、ゲイ文学または同性愛関係について話しましょう
when so much attention
とても注目されているとき
such a work
そんな仕事
it actually has to be noticed
それは実際に気づかなければなりません
This is a work from around 1840 in the 19th century
19世紀、1840年頃の作品です
it can be so strong
とても強いかもしれない
so direct and so hot
とても直接的でとても熱い
to write about same-sex relationships
同性愛について書く
And it's placed under the frame of a female partner's men's clothing
そしてそれは女性パートナーの紳士服のフレームの下に置かれます
We can also see that I exceed a very large amount of time
非常に長い時間を超えていることもわかります
But I think you guys should let me finish, right?
でも、皆さんは私に終わらせるべきだと思いますよね？
ok we can see
わかりました、わかります
it has some very interesting descriptions
非常に興味深い説明がいくつかあります
Not only the intensity that just described this emotion
この感情を表現したばかりの激しさだけではなく
At the same time it also shows you the intensity of this lust
同時にこの欲望の強さも見せてくれる
We just talked about this novel
ちょうどこの小説について話しました
because it has this female companion
この女性コンパニオンがいるからです
Reverted to the design of the plot like a female
女性らしいプロットのデザインに戻しました
So the relationship between the two heroines is in
ということで、ヒロイン二人の関係は
Women, women, men, women, among the various possibilities
女、女、男、女、様々な可能性の中で変化していく
so let's look at this
それでこれを見てみましょう
This description is talking about
この説明が話しているのは、
Both of them are still dressed as men
二人ともまだ男装してる
Of course they know each other is female
もちろん二人はお互いが女性であることを知っています
But outsiders think they are men
しかし部外者は彼らを男性だと思っている
so one of them
それでそのうちの1人が
he is also married
彼も結婚しています
we'll talk later
後で話す
In this story of a woman disguised as a man
男装した女の物語
This woman who is accompanied by a man must marry
男性を連れた女性は結婚しなければならない
because if she doesn't get married
なぜなら彼女が結婚しなかったら
she can't hide
彼女は隠すことができない
The fact that she is female
彼女が女性であるという事実
So we look here to say
そこで私たちはここでこう言いたいのです
one of them
それらの中の一つ
where is this lady
この女性はどこですか
What about the lady in men's clothing?
紳士服を着た女性はどうでしょうか？
just tell her cousin
彼女のいとこにだけ伝えてください
your sister-in-law is my wife
あなたの義理の妹は私の妻です
I went to the palace today
今日は宮殿に行ってきました
so what
だから何
my room is empty
私の部屋は空です
do you want to come
来たいですか
So
それで
I treat you as
私はあなたを次のように扱います
I put my good brother
良い兄弟を入れました
Just treat yourself like you are a beautiful jiao'e
自分が美しいジャオエであるかのように自分を扱ってください
In fact, she is simply a beautiful Jiao'e
実際、彼女はただの美しいジャオエです
what about after bed
就寝後はどうですか
this brother this sister
この弟 この妹
I don't even know how to describe her
彼女をどう説明したらいいのかさえ分からない
please imagine
想像してください
because of the
のせいで
her game
彼女のゲーム
Her sex game is too complicated
彼女のセックスゲームは複雑すぎる
she just said
彼女はちょうど言った
let me take your hat off
帽子を脱がせてください
let me take off your shoes
靴を脱がせてください
is it cold
寒いですか？
I'll cover you with the quilt
キルトであなたを覆ってあげます
Then what
じゃあ何
after falling asleep
眠りについた後
this brother this sister
この弟 この妹
He saw this sleeping
彼はこれが寝ているのを見た
What about this girl with a world-class face?
世界クラスの顔を持つこの女の子はどうですか？
He said he saw my brother drunk
彼は私の兄が酔っているのを見たと言いました
red face
赤い顔
so beautiful
とても美しい
I spread this back into me pulling my beloved brother
私はこれを私の中に広げて、愛する兄弟を引き寄せました
We are like a pair of mandarin ducks
私たちはつがいのおしどりのようなものです
hold here
ここで待ってください
so connected
とてもつながっています
It's really beautiful, just like this water
本当に美しい、この水のように
Compassion is average, right?
思いやりは平均的ですよね？
Flowers are not as beautiful as female genuine
花はメスの本物ほど美しくない
Oh by the way
あっ、そういえば
Let me explain by the way
ちなみに説明させてください
Both of them know that they are actually
二人とも自分が本当はそうだということを知っている
a man's fiancee
男の婚約者
they are cousins
彼らはいとこです
At the same time, he was engaged to his cousin
同時に彼は従妹と婚約した
So he said Huan Lang
それで彼はフアン・ランと言った
Huan Lang is their common wedding dress
Huan Lang は彼らの共通のウェディングドレスです
He said such a beautiful person
とても美しい人だと彼は言いました
our maiden dress
私たちの乙女ドレス
He hasn't touched it yet
彼はまだそれに触れていない
it was me first
最初は私でした
Ha ha ha ha
ハハハッハッハ
I'm Hengkui, I stand first
私はヘンクイ、最初に立ちます
It's a pity, if we get married one day, I'll have to give it up to someone else.
残念ですが、いつか結婚するとしても、他の人に譲らなければなりません。
It's like Wang Wei, right?
ワン・ウェイみたいな感じですかね？
Such a beautiful person, I actually want to give it up to someone else
とても素敵な人なので、本当は他の人に譲りたいのですが
instead of my beloved
私の愛する人の代わりに
it's a pity
それは残念だ
So we see this inside
それで、私たちはこれを内部で見ます
On the one hand, he is lust, on the other hand, he is emotion, and he is a comrade in arms
一方では彼は欲望であり、他方では彼は感情であり、彼は戦友である
He's another competitor with men
彼もまた男性の競争相手だ
There are too many layers
層が多すぎる
It is our identity as a contemporary reader that can be imagined
想像できるのは、現代の読者としての私たちのアイデンティティです。
It's fun, but time is of the essence and I have to hurry up to the bottom
楽しいけど時間は限られているので急いで下まで行かなければなりません
I'm going to talk about this faster and faster.
これについては、これからどんどん話していきます。
This is the 1860s
これは 1860 年代です
The deduction of this era, this drama is really getting faster and faster
この時代の推理、本当にこのドラマはどんどん早くなっている
After the Taiping Heavenly Kingdom War in 1861, Jiangnan was dilapidated
1861年の太平天国戦争の後、江南は荒廃した
But we have seen a work like this
しかし、私たちはこのような作品を見てきました
a female author who took advantage of
を利用した女性作家
Taking advantage of the war in the Taiping Heavenly Kingdom
太平天国の戦乱に乗じて
because of her mother
彼女の母親のせいで
In the chaos of the Taiping Heavenly Kingdom?
太平天国の混乱の中で？
Scared. Simply put, had a stroke.
怖いです。簡単に言えば、脳卒中を起こしたのです。
scared to have a stroke
脳卒中が怖い
so bedridden
とても寝たきりです
So what about this woman?
それで、この女性はどうですか？
she very conveniently
彼女はとても都合よく
That's great, I solemnly say
それは素晴らしいことです、私は厳粛に言います
Then I won't get married, I'll stay and take care of mom
それなら私は結婚しない、ここに残ってお母さんの面倒を見るよ
She took this opportunity to escape marriage
彼女はこの機会を利用して結婚から逃れた
she will stay in this family forever
彼女は永遠にこの家族に残るでしょう
Even after her mother passed away
母親が亡くなった後も
she is still not married
彼女はまだ結婚していません
But stay in this native family
でもこの地元の家族に留まってください
she has been creating all her life
彼女は生涯を通じて創作を続けてきた
She wrote a novel called Goldfish Garden
彼女は「金魚の庭」という小説を書きました
And there is a heroine called Qian Shurong
そして銭淑栄というヒロインがいる。
let's see this
これを見てみましょう
The same former Su-yong's inner monologue
同じ元スヨンの内なる独白
She said that my former Shurong
彼女は私の元Shuronが言った。
me as a woman
女性としての私
I can only hug Lulu for the rest of my life
残りの人生はルルを抱きしめるしかない
nothing counts
何も重要​​ではありません
what is this
これは何ですか
i don't want to live like this
こんなふうに生きたくない
This is called walking towards the world
これを世界に向かって歩くという
I must proudly mark the name
誇りを持ってその名を刻まなければなりません
i don't want to live
生きたくない
Disillusionment is like Chengdu must leave something in the world
幻滅は成都が世界に何かを残さなければならないようなもの
Then he said that there are so many high-minded people in this history
それから彼は、この歴史には志の高い人がたくさんいると言いました。
Talented women, I want to be like them
才能ある女性たち、私も彼女たちのようになりたい
I want Wan Gu Yangming
王古陽明が欲しい
What about such a volunteer?
そんなボランティアはどうでしょうか？
There are also women in the novel we have seen before, right?
以前見た小説にも女性が出てきますよね？
but they are hard to do
しかし、それらは難しいです
isn't it
ではない？
They all have to finally come to terms with going back to being women.
彼らは皆、最終的には女性に戻ることを受け入れなければなりません。
The fate of returning to the family's duty
家族の義務に戻る運命
So what do we say about this
それで、これについては何と言いますか
The following is compared to the author's own choice
以下は著者自身の選択と比較されます
I think he's very autobiographical
彼はとても自伝的だと思う
He said
彼は言った
Husband loves wife, loves wife, respects, suffers from dementia and conceives daughter to fuck
夫は妻を愛し、愛を尊重し、認知症を患い、娘を妊娠する
Love, evil, evil, Xiao Nan, respect for the future
愛、悪、悪、シャオナン、未来への敬意
With the so-called bubble talk, I fell into a pitfall
いわゆるバブルトークで落とし穴にはまった
no sea swimming pool
海のプールはありません
Such a rejection of marriage
そんな結婚拒否
There must be factors of the whole society at that time behind it
その背景には当時の社会全体の要因があるはずだ
Then we also mentioned
それから私達も言いました
This is also supported by a certain kind of religious transcendence pursuit
これは、ある種の宗教的超越性の追求によっても裏付けられています。
So on the one hand, it wants to escape from the secular society
だから一方では世俗社会から抜け出したい。
and home network
そしてホームネットワーク
On the one hand, it seeks a higher
一方で、より高いものを追求したいと考えています。
No matter whether it is construction or spiritual, it is a kind of transcendence
建築であれスピリチュアルであれ、それはある種の超越性である
So can it be done?
それで、それはできるでしょうか？
In the 1860's it became doable
1860年代にはそれが可能になった
Then in this goldfish garden
そしてこの金魚園で
This heroine named Qian Shurong
このヒロインは銭淑栄という名前です
She's with a woman who shares her ambitions
彼女は野心を共有する女性と一緒にいる
This woman is her woman who married her
この女性は彼女と結婚した女性です
These two people will be a man and a woman all their lives.
この二人は一生男と女です。
This kind of image has lived leisurely for a lifetime
一生のんびり生きてきたようなイメージ
Before this kind of imagination, no female writer dared to think like this
この種の想像力以前には、このような考えを敢えてした女性作家はいなかった
So here we are seeing the change of the times
ここに時代の変化が見られます
The same as we just said in this story
この話でさっき言ったのと同じこと
A woman who disguises herself as a man must marry
男装した女は結婚しなければならない
So the point is how do you design this
重要なのは、これをどのようにデザインするかです
A woman who marries a woman accepts the marriage
女性と結婚する女性は結婚を受け入れる
Then each author will have a different imagination
そうすれば作者それぞれの想像力が違うだろう
Then the setting in the goldfish garden is
そして金魚園の舞台は、
The woman she married and what she thinks
結婚した女性とその考え
Almost everyone thinks that marriage is meaningless to marry a man
ほとんどの人は、男性と結婚するのは結婚に意味がないと考えています。
we are fine
私たちは大丈夫
The two of us are good friends and close friends
私たち二人は仲が良くて親友です
We walk through life hand in hand like this
私たちはこうして手を取り合って人生を歩んでいきます
How good are the two of them?
二人はどれくらい仲が良いのでしょうか？
so good that their relationship will gradually simulate
とても良いので、彼らの関係は徐々にシミュレートされます
or even beyond the intimacy of husband and wife
あるいは夫婦の親密さを超えてさえ
For example, this section of Tianmian
たとえば、天面のこのセクション
This is Qian Shurong, the female companion who wears men's clothing. She is on a business trip.
こちらは出張中の紳士服を着た女性コンパニオン、銭淑栄です。
then left her beloved lady at home
そして最愛の女性を家に残して
Then the lady said
するとその女性は言いました
Whoops I'm lying in my yard all over
おっと、私はずっと庭に横たわっています
I miss him so much, I can't help crying when I think about talking about wolves
彼がいなくてとても寂しい、オオカミについて話すことを考えると涙が止まらない
thinking about him all night
一晩中彼のことを考えている
I'm like this girl who lost his partner
私はパートナーを失ったこの小さな男のようなものです
can't fall asleep
眠れない
My beloved has been away for so long and has not heard from me
私の愛する人は長い間離れていて、私から連絡がありません
I'm really lovesick, I've lost weight
私は本当に恋に悩んでいて、体重が減りました
Then such an emotional description
そうすると、こんな感情的な描写が
If we pull him out of his veins
もし私たちが彼を血管から引き抜いたら
you will feel that this is a
これはだと感じるでしょう。
An ordinary display of love between husband and wife, right?
夫婦間の普通の愛情表現ですよね？
Or let's look at the following sentences
あるいは次の文を見てみましょう
This is writing about this former Shurong
これはこの元シュロンについて書いています
he will be very flirtatious
彼はとても浮気するでしょう
He will use sweet words to make his wife happy
彼は妻を幸せにするために甘い言葉を使うだろう
Then the lady scolded him and said
すると女性は彼を叱ってこう言いました。
Your girlfriend is only a year old
あなたのガールフレンドはまだ1歳です
you feel like this
あなたはこんな感じです
this exile
この追放者
You are such a fool, suck this gray shoe
あなたは本当に愚かです、この灰色の靴を吸ってください
Joke, have you forgotten your real face?
冗談、本当の顔を忘れたの？
What is the original face?
本来の顔は何ですか？
You're a woman, of course.
もちろんあなたは女性です。
good
良い
but the problem is
しかし問題は
If the imagination of the story says it's going to succeed
物語の想像力がそれが成功すると言っているなら
That is to say
つまり
This Qian Shurong must be able to act as a man
この銭守栄は男として行動できなければなりません
successfully retired
無事に退職しました
get retired seam
引退した縫い目を取得する
And then have a good time with his wife
そして奥さんと楽しい時間を過ごしましょう
For the rest of his life, he must forget his true colors
残りの人生、彼は自分の本当の姿を忘れなければならない
How can I forget my true colors
どうすれば本当の自分の色を忘れられるでしょうか
One of the necessary conditions
必要な条件の一つ
That is, he must be able to successfully simulate the relationship between men and women
つまり、男女の関係をうまくシミュレーションできなければならない。
what about this time
今回はどうですか
Female writers will have a lot of imagination and expression of this kind of love language
女性作家は、この種の愛の言葉をたくさんの想像力と表現力で表現するでしょう
that is to say
つまり
Although the matter of dressing up as a man
男装の件ですが
he's not though
彼はそうではないけど
It's about dressing up as a man.
男装することです。
Definitely not something you just do when you get out of the house
家から出たときにだけ行うものではありません
If you think about it, if I decide today
よく考えたら今日決めたら
I'm Meng Lijun, I'm going to dress up as a man
私は孟立軍、男装します
I can't wear a dress and put on lipstick at home
家ではドレスも着ないし口紅も塗れない
When I went out, I hurriedly changed into men's clothes
出かける時は急いで紳士服に着替えました
Put on the boots, no, that wouldn't be a successful drag
ブーツを履いてください、いいえ、それは成功しないでしょう
I have to put myself through and through
私は自分自身を徹底的に突き詰めなければなりません
reinvented as a male
男性として生まれ変わった
From dress up to speech to behavior and even love language
服装から話し方、行動、さらには愛の言葉まで
have to be male
男性でなければならない
this costume will be successful
この衣装は成功するだろう
But if he succeeds, is it still a disguise?
しかし、もし成功したとしても、それはやはり偽装なのだろうか？
We can see the imagination of a woman disguised as a man
男装した女の想像力が見える
how many layers of complexity
複雑さの層は何層か
He's about what's called humanity, what's called gender
彼は人間性と呼ばれるもの、ジェンダーと呼ばれるものについて話している
Identity, the nature of gender, erotic relationships, etc.
アイデンティティ、性別の性質、エロティックな関係など。
Some of these introspections are ours until today
これらの内省の一部は今日まで私たちのものです
I'm afraid they're all still tangled up with complex issues
残念ながら、彼らはまだ複雑な問題に巻き込まれているようです
i am a greedy person
私は貪欲な人間です
So I always hope that in a speech
だから私はいつもスピーチでそう願っています
Try to share as much as possible with my audience
視聴者とできるだけ多くのことを共有するように努めてください
so please give me two more minutes
だからあと2分だけ時間をください
This is also a work from the late 19th century.
こちらも19世紀後半の作品です。
It is a post-Taiping work
太平天国以降の作品です
This work is called Zi Xu Ji
この作品は『子徐記』と呼ばれています。
The title of this work gives us a very...
この作品のタイトルはとても印象的です...
how to say?
どのように言って？
This is very hypocritical, isn't it?
これはとても偽善的ですよね。
It's all just imagination, don't take it seriously
すべて単なる想像ですので、真剣に考えないでください
But what?
でも何？
This novel also resolutely demonstrates
この小説も断固として示している。
the female writer
この女性作家
He wants to imagine a story about a woman who refuses to look back
彼は振り返ることを拒否した女性の物語を想像したいと考えています
This is a manuscript written by Zixu
これは子胥が書いた原稿です
Well, Zixu Ji actually has a quite moving story.
さて、子胥記には実に感動的な物語があります。
This is Wang Ou rewarding him after writing Zixu Ji
これは子胥記を書いた後、彼に褒美を与える王応です
This manuscript was inherited by his daughter
この原稿は娘に受け継がれた
Then after the daughter inherits
そして娘が相続した後は
When I brought it to my husband's house, his husband's...
夫の家に持っていくと、夫の...
Women's Literature is Herself
女流文学は自分自身である
then her daughter
それから彼女の娘
her daughter's daughter
彼女の娘の娘
female inheritance
女性の相続
So she's totally an heir to a woman
つまり彼女は完全に女性の後継者だ
She and everything else have male inheritance
彼女と他のすべてのものは男性の遺伝を持っています
are different
異なっています
then the impressive thing is
それから印象的なのは
This thing has been around since the 1860s
これは1860年代から存在しています
passed the test of time
時の試練に合格した
During the Cultural Revolution in the 1960s
1960年代の文化大革命中
women in this house
この家の女性たち
descendants of this author
この作者の子孫
are risking their lives
命を危険にさらしている
to protect the high book
高い本を守るために
they didn't give it up
彼らはそれを諦めなかった
You have to imagine something like this
このようなことを想像する必要があります
If it was discovered at the time
もしその時に発見されていたら
what a disaster it could be to that family
それはその家族にとってどれほど大きな災難になるだろうか
But this family has worked hard to preserve this high capital.
しかし、この家族はこの高額な資本を維持するために最善を尽くしています。
Then probably a few years ago
それからおそらく数年前
donate money to this
これにお金を寄付してください
Probably to the local provincial or municipal government or something
おそらく地方自治体か何かに提出されるでしょう
So behind this story is actually
この話の裏には実は
The story behind the preservation of this text
本書保存の経緯
Actually it is
実はそうなんです
Just witnessed a talk about this novel
この小説についての講演を目撃しました
How it's possible to be a soul treasure passed down from generation to generation by women
女性が世代から世代へと受け継がれる魂の宝となることがどのようにして可能なのか
such a background
そんな背景
good
良い
sorry i didn't write it down
ごめんなさい、書いてませんでした
Okay, it's okay, I read it well again
わかった、大丈夫、もう一度よく読んだ
So what's in this subtitle?
それで、このサブタイトルには何が入っているのでしょうか？
his heroine begins by saying
彼のヒロインはこう言い始める
I want red bayberry to be a man
ヤマモモは男になってほしい
And I'm definitely not going back as a woman
そして私は絶対に女性に戻るつもりはない
If one day I'm exposed
いつか暴露されたら
i will die
私が死ぬ
so in this story
だからこの話では
What about the heroine?
ヒロインはどうでしょうか？
in the end
最終的には
he died
彼は死んだ
He absolutely refuses to follow the norms of society.
彼は社会の規範に従うことを絶対に拒否します。
So we can probably see
だからおそらく見えるでしょう
This Zixuji is similar to the era of Jin Yuyuan just now
この子胥は今の金玉源の時代に似ている
They all manifested a new, absolute will
全員が新たな絶対の意志を表明した
The will to break social norms
社会の常識を打ち破る意志
But what?
でも何？
They imagined the consequences differently
彼らは異なる結果を想像しました
Jin Yuyuan's practice
ジン・ユユアンのアプローチ
More optimistic, he imagined a successful companion
もっと楽観的に、彼は成功した仲間を想像した
And the author of this memoir
そしてこの回想録の著者は
imagined a woman
女性を想像した
the pursuit of this life
この人生の追求
In the end there will be no way to resist the system
結局システムに抵抗する方法はなくなる
But you must use your own life to live and die
しかし、生きるのも死ぬのも自分の命を使わなければなりません
such a design
そのようなデザイン
So this one is from the 1860s onwards
つまり、これは1860年代以降のものです
two different reactions
2つの異なる反応
Well, finally, it's time to come to the conclusion.
さて、ついに結論を出す時が来ました。
So soon I will share with you a little
近いうちに少しシェアさせていただきます
I am about female elastic magnetic novel
私は女性の弾性磁気小説についてです
Some understanding of this creative form
この創造的な形式についてのある程度の理解
The first one is the female elastic magnetic novel
第一弾は女性弾性磁気小説です
it's very autobiographical
それはとても自伝的だ
because these women writers
なぜなら、この女性作家たちは
they are holding
彼らは持っています
Refusing to let myself follow the disillusionment of the flesh
肉体の幻滅に従うことを拒否する
creative consciousness
創造的な意識
They hope that they can achieve immortality
彼らは不死を達成できることを望んでいます
So this creative consciousness
つまり、この創造的な意識は
will keep them in their texts
テキストに残しておきます
to show yourself
自分自身を見せるために
These little books, although they imagined a lot of strange stories about relatives
これらの小さな本は、親戚に関するたくさんの奇妙な物語を想像していましたが、
But it will also write a lot of daily life related to women
女性にまつわる日常もたくさん書きます
For example, eating, for example, giving gifts
たとえば、食べること、たとえば、贈り物をすること
For example, production, etc.
例えば、制作など。
So many women's unique experiences
女性ならではの体験がたくさん
The third one is like Li Qingzhao, who doesn’t just write about personal emotions
3番目は、個人的な感情だけを書かない李清照さんのようです
Also write the same as the master of the country
国の主とも同じように書きます。
What about these female authors, they don’t just write about the emotions in this regulation
これらの女性作家はどうですか、彼らはこの規制の感情についてだけを書いているわけではありません
They will put their novels in a big historical framework
彼らは自分の小説を大きな歴史的枠組みの中に置くだろう
They like to think of writing novels as writing history.
彼らは小説を書くことを歴史を書くことだと考えることを好みます。
is a reflection on history
歴史を振り返るものです
Well even we didn't have that example today
まあ、今日はその例はありませんでしたが
But there are some novels, it's just that I want to rewrite the famous history
でも小説もいくつかある、ただ有名な歴史を書き換えたいだけだ
Such a will is writing
そんな遺言が書いてある
So what next we can see
さて、次に何が見えるでしょうか
From the example of Liu Huameng just now
先ほどの劉華蒙の例から
We can see that this female writer
この女性作家が
talk about this novel
この小説について話す
It is said that this relatively flexible genre expresses very strongly
比較的自由度の高いジャンルで、表現力が非常に強いと言われています。
But in the genre of poetry
しかし詩というジャンルにおいては
feelings that cannot be expressed
表現できない感情
same-sex love
同性愛
So in the end we
それで結局私たちは
In the end, it's actually a question
結局のところ、それは本当に質問です
That is, from these many works
つまり、このたくさんの作品の中から、
we can really explore
私たちは本当に探検することができます
these women writers
この女性作家たち
social norms
社会規範
relationship with the so-called system
いわゆるシステムとの関係
Of course they resist
もちろん彼らは抵抗する
Of course they are counterbalanced
もちろんカウンターバランスです
But they often have to be dewormed too
しかし、多くの場合、駆虫も必要です
So in the twentieth or twenty-first century
それで20世紀か21世紀には
when we re-read these novels
これらの小説を再読すると
Never simply
決して単純に
is this feminism
これがフェミニズムですか
or is it a revolution
それとも革命なのか
Is this a gender revolution
これはジェンダー革命ですか
such a single thought
そんなたった一つの思い
look at these works
これらの作品を見てください
ok let's skip this
わかりました、これはスキップしましょう
Finally, as a New Year's gift for everyone today
最後に、今日は皆様へのお年玉として
I want everyone to appreciate
みんなに評価してもらいたい
two minutes this is contemporary
2分、これは現代的だ
very famous
非常に有名
Real erotic fisting of an actress
女優のリアルなエロフィストファック
Ms. Sheng Xiaojun's performance
シェン・シャオジュンさんの演技
This is Mulan Ci
ムーラン・シーです
everyone will recite
みんなが暗唱するだろう
Let's see Mulan Ci
ムーラン・シーを見てみよう
If you use Peng Xi to perform
Peng Xi を使用してパフォーマンスを行う場合
what is called
と呼ばれるもの
and look at the age is you not the day
そして年齢を見てください、あなたはその日ではありませんか
Thank you very much Chief Hu for his speech today
本日は胡主席のご講演誠にありがとうございました
I believe you enjoyed an evening of literary fiction sounds as much as I did
あなたも私と同じように文学小説の音の夜を楽しんだと思います
Not only he is greedy, but I am also greedy
彼が貪欲であるだけでなく、私も貪欲です
I've been wanting to hear it all
ずっと聞きたかったんだ
Based on my usual experience in hosting meetings
会議を主催する際の私の普段の経験に基づく
I interrupted him about half an hour ago.
30分ほど前に私は彼の話を中断しました。
I can't bear to interrupt him today.
今日は彼の邪魔をするのは忍びない。
Especially for me, someone with a background in science, engineering and mathematics
特に科学、工学、数学のバックグラウンドを持つ私にとっては
This opportunity to enjoy the voice of this spa novel
この機会に温泉小説の音声を楽しんでください
So sorry and don't really have much time
申し訳ありませんが、あまり時間がありません
Let me ask you this question
この質問をさせてください
I think unless you are very interested in this stuff
よほどこのことに興味がない限りは
I guess just open up a question or two
1 つか 2 つ質問を開いていただければと思います
ok please
はい、お願いします
ask the professor
教授に聞く
the one just mentioned
今言ったもの
That is to say, a woman disguised as a man became a high official
つまり、男装した女性が高官になったのだ。
So during tutoring, will you commit the crime of the Seventh Army?
それで、家庭教師中に第7軍の犯罪を犯しますか？
Yes Nadine Minger asks you
はい、ナディーン・ミンジャーがあなたに尋ねます
That is to say, these protagonists, they all
つまり、この主人公たちは全員、
I want to make myself a boy
自分を男の子にしたい
right
右
Then I was wondering if they were modern people
それで彼らは現代人なのかと思ったのですが
then they should be
それなら彼らはそうあるべきです
like we are very transgender now
私たちは今とてもトランスジェンダーであるように
right
右
the rule is
ルールは
And the same-sex business, right?
そして同性愛ビジネスですよね？
Thanks
ありがとう
thanks for your question
ご質問ありがとうございます
yes
はい
Disguising a woman as a man is called reversing yin and yang, which is a crime of deceiving the emperor
女性を男に偽装することは陰陽反転と呼ばれ、皇帝を欺く罪となります。
His crime is not just because of bullying the king
彼の罪は国王をいじめたことだけではない
At the same time, it is also because he disturbed the order of heaven and earth
それは同時に天地の秩序を乱したからでもある
so it's really a felony
だからそれは本当に重罪だよ
It is precisely because of this
まさにこのためです
So the heroine in this novel
さて、この小説のヒロインは、
They will all be under a lot of pressure
彼らは皆、大きなプレッシャーにさらされるだろう
Like why in the story of Meng Lijun
孟立軍の物語のような理由
the emperor can oppress him saying
皇帝はこう言って彼を弾圧することができる
Come on and develop this affair with me a little bit
さあ、私とこの関係を少し発展させてください
Just because the emperor can grab him by the throat
皇帝が喉を掴むことができるからといって
right
右
I just want to expose you
ただあなたを暴露したいだけです
you are capital crime
あなたは極悪犯罪者です
I can't spare you
私はあなたを許すことができません
So in that story is
それで、その話の中で、
The queen mother came forward and said to forgive him.
王太后は名乗り出て、彼を許してくれと言った。
So so indeed this is a key point
確かにこれは重要なポイントです
All this related text inside
このすべての関連テキストが含まれています
will ponder over this issue.
この問題について熟考するだろう。
Each author has his own interpretation
作者それぞれに独自の解釈がある
like the one we just saw
私たちが今見たもののように
The story of the former Shurong
かつてのシュロンの物語
he is not
彼ではない
Instead of Qian Shurong
銭淑栄の代わりに
another one
もう一つ
The story of Zixu
子胥の物語
won't he die
彼は死ぬのではないか
it's me who dies
死ぬのは私です
good
良い
then as for
それからについては
Yun’s second question just now is about their
ユンの今の 2 番目の質問は、彼らについてです。
Are we going to treat them as transgender in modern times?
現代では彼らをトランスジェンダーとして扱うのでしょうか？
Or maybe this can't be called a transsexual?
それともこれはニューハーフとは言えないのでしょうか？
what is it called
それはなんと呼ばれていますか
not just gay
ゲイだけじゃない
should have a proper name
適切な名前があるはずです
I dare not now
今はあえてしない
A question of gender identity
性同一性の問題
it's a very complex question
それはとても複雑な質問です
It is also different in each text
それぞれのテキストでも異なります
I personally feel like Liu Huameng
個人的には劉華蒙のような気がします
or a goldfish garden
金魚園とか
author of goldfish garden
金魚庭の作者
Exhibits very strong celibacy
非常に強い独身主義を示す
the need not to marry
結婚しない必要性
But what about his celibacy
しかし彼の独身生活はどうなのだろうか
Does it have anything to do with his gender identity?
それは彼の性自認と何か関係がありますか？
It's more ambiguous, not so clear
もっと曖昧で、それほど明確ではない
We can see that he certainly describes
彼が確かに次のように説明していることがわかります。
His so-called wife who is also female
いわゆる彼の妻（同じく女性）
this is living a good married life
これは良い結婚生活を送っています
but in the novel
しかし小説では
you don't feel very
あなたはあまり感じません
strong desire
強い欲求
Lust Carnal desire Rarely
欲望 肉欲 まれに
But Liu Huameng's work is different
しかし、劉華蒙氏の作品は違います。
I think Liu Huameng's work
劉華蒙の作品だと思います
what is conveyed in
何が伝わるのか
this homosexual
この同性愛者
intensity depth etc.
強度の深さなど
cannot be ignored
無視できない
That is to say, we can't simply say
つまり、単純に言うことはできないのです
This is the intimacy between girls
これが女の子同士の親密さ
Are you afraid of handing in? What? No.
提出するのが怖いですか? 何ですか? いいえ。
if we face it honestly
正直に向き合えば
words in that text
その文中の単語
we will know
私たちは知るでしょう
that is gay
それはゲイです
But does that mean
でもそれって意味あるの？
He has a problem with his gender identity
彼は自分の性自認に問題を抱えている
i think that's something else
それは別のことだと思う
because homosexuality does not mean
同性愛という意味ではないので、
His gender identity is different
彼の性自認は違う
right?
右？
So I think that should be discussed separately
だからそれは分けて議論すべきだと思う
But in these works
しかし、これらの作品では
is there any author
著者はいますか
The writer moved to modern times alone
作家は単身現代へ転移
He'll say I'm going transgender
彼は私がトランスジェンダーになると言うだろう
I dare not say I think it is possible
あえて言えませんが、それは可能だと思います
But I can't see it from the text
でも文面からは見えない
very clear evidence
非常に明確な証拠
Well, I think because of time
まあ、時間のせいだと思います
we probably can't help it
おそらく仕方ないでしょう
Today I am really grateful to Chief Hu
今日は胡主任に本当に感謝しています
his greedy novel
彼の貪欲な小説
Not his deep interpretation
彼の深い解釈ではない
we probably don't understand
私たちはおそらく理解できないでしょう
I think I probably know and understand a little
おそらく少しは知っていて理解していると思います
Maybe the women here can understand more deeply
ここの女性の方が理解が深まるかもしれない
At least knowing I can have something to watch when I retire
少なくとも、引退したら何か見ることができるとわかっている
Thank you again Chief Hu Thank you
改めてありがとうございます胡主任、ありがとうございます